Bryce shrinking every minute...
ブライスは毎分縮んでいきます...
Karamati because I needed...
カラマティ、必要だったから…
life...
人生...
to jump over gate and man....
門も人も飛び越える……。
now Siro appears out of nowhere.
どこからともなくシロが現れます。
He has two brothers and favorite….
彼には2人の兄弟がいて、お気に入りは…。
so he is named 6...
それで彼は6と名付けられました...
Siro appear in this movie.
この映画にはシロが登場します。
He has 4 brothers and 1 sister.
彼には4人の兄弟と1人の妹がいます。
He always been before hisoscope.
彼はいつもヒスコープの前にいました。
Here is a version.
ここにバージョンがあります。
Lemmemayın siro S this thing
Lemmemayın siro S このこと
you have to get by ASAP.
できるだけ早く対処しなければなりません。
Can much beat Master Ching Somebody's現在...
Can much beat Master Ching Somebody's現在...
Thank you.
ありがとう。
Yang Cuisheng, the former county magistrate of our Matsu County
ヤン・クイシェン、元馬祖県の県判事
mazu county magistrate
媽祖郡判事
Members
メンバー
today we have a
今日は
please sit down
座ってください
The topic is
トピックは
Archaeological excavations on Xianya
西安の考古学的発掘
Talking about the Unearthed Story of the Old Man Liang
発掘された梁老人の物語について語る
I want to measure what the old man unearthed
おじいさんが掘り出したものを測りたい
among the newspapers
新聞の中には
in learning
学習中
reports with a lot of information
多くの情報を含むレポート
So these important archaeological excavations
したがって、これらの重要な考古学的発掘は
Everyone must notice
誰もが気づくはずだ
our knowledge misses
私たちの知識が欠けている
Because every year the humanities and social sciences
なぜなら、人文科学と社会科学は毎年、
only four times
たったの4回
so it's a great honor
とても光栄なことです
great honor
大変名誉なこと
Then our Mr. Chen
それから私たちのチェンさん
Actually retired from Academia Sinica
実は中央研究院を退職した
But his previous research
しかし、彼の以前の研究では、
then schedule this talk
次に、このトークをスケジュールします
there is an important reason
重要な理由があります
It is the beginning of the data equivalent to the elderly
高齢者相当データの始まりです
at the time of publication
出版当時
Academician Xu Zhuoen of Academia Sinica
中央研究院院士徐卓恩氏
He Yueren is in the United States
何岳人はアメリカにいます
Ancient archaeology, paleontology, DNA, etc. are very, very concerned
古代考古学、古生物学、DNAなどは非常に懸念されています。
So he wrote me that email several times specifically
それで彼は私にそのメールを何回も具体的に書いてくれました
He said you as the vice president
彼はあなたを副大統領だと言いました
he this is a major and important discovery
これは重大かつ重要な発見です
He should try to give Mr. Chen an award
彼は陳氏に賞を与えるように努めるべきだ
I said I don't have a prize
賞品はないと言いました
So so I don't have an award to give to Mr. Chen
ということで、チェンさんにあげる賞はありません。
Especially the humanities and social science awards are very, very few
特に人文科学と社会科学の賞は非常に少ないです
Then some prizes may be too small for Mr. Chen
そうなると、一部の賞品はチェンさんにとっては小さすぎるかもしれません
Well at least I don't have it I don't have it
まあ、少なくとも私はそれを持っていません、私はそれを持っていません
I said I thought about it and couldn't think of a way
考えてみたけど方法が思いつかないと言いました
Later, I thought that the feast of knowledge is actually an occasion for affirming important achievements
後で私は、知識の饗宴は実際には重要な成果を確認する機会であると考えました。
So there is such an arrangement
そういう仕組みもあるんですね
Because Mr. Chen has usually knowledge feast if yours is usually not retired
なぜなら、陳氏は通常、退職者ではないのに、知識の饗宴を持っているからです。
Well, those outside the hospital are of course still working.
もちろん、病院外の人たちはまだ働いています。
Because I have been retired for many years
引退してもう何年も経つから
So today we are looking for this opportunity
さて、今日は特にこの機会を探しています
There is a reason for arranging this speech
このスピーチを企画したのには理由があります
Well, I think this is the first thing to explain
まあ、これが最初に説明すべきことだと思います
It is Xu Zhuoenyuan because he has ancient history before
彼は以前に古代の歴史を持っているので、徐卓園です。
He has been concerned about this ancient archaeological
彼はこの古代考古学に関心を持っていました
very concerned
とても心配です
he this
彼はこれ
I want to keep this around 2011
2011年くらいまでに留めておきたい
What about the Mazu Liang Island archaeological team led by Mr. Chen?
陳氏率いる媽祖梁島考古学チームはどうだろうか？
Execute excavation work
掘削工事を実施します
Well, two human remains were unearthed.
さて、二人の遺体が発掘されました。
Named Bright Island Man
ブライト・アイランド・マンと名付けられた
After the human bones have been cleaned and trimmed
人骨を洗浄してトリミングした後
Delivery to Max Planck, Germany
ドイツのマックス・プランクに納品
the Max Blanc Institute
マックス・ブラン研究所
To do this DNA extraction analysis
この DNA 抽出分析を行うには
very good results
非常に良い結果
Because Taiwan is a wet
台湾は湿気が多いので
hot and humid place
高温多湿な場所
So many of our ancient bones
非常に多くの古代の骨
Difficult to extract DNA
DNAの抽出が難しい
so this
したがって、この
This is surprisingly good
これが意外と良いんです
as far as i know
私の知る限りでは
i am not an archaeologist
私は考古学者ではありません
but as far as i know
しかし、私が知っている限りでは
unexpectedly good
予想外に良い
So this is a very difficult achievement
したがって、これは非常に難しい成果です
Then after the comparison
それでは比較後
got a result that is
という結果が得られました
Quantitative guides are 8000 years away from today
定量的なガイドは今日から 8000 年後
Or earlier, the southeastern part of the Asian continent
それ以前は、アジア大陸の南東部でした。
aborigines
原住民
people of the same blood
同じ血を引く人々
Can be called the original Nandao Yuzu
オリジナルのナンダオユズとも言えます
They most likely came from the southeast coast of mainland China
彼らは中国本土の南東海岸から来た可能性が最も高い
thus come
したがって来てください
Therefore, the formation of the Nandaoyu tribe
したがって、ナンダオユ族の形成は
can be pushed back nearly 8,000 years
8,000年近く遡ることができる
This is because quite specialized
かなり専門的だから
I can't quite grasp it either
私もよく理解できません
I am the Yu family from about 8000 years ago
私は約8000年前のユ族です
8000 years ago this
8000年前はこれ
Then the other is today's keynote speaker
それからもう一人は今日の基調講演者です
What about Professor Chen Zhongyi?
陳仲儀教授はどうですか？
is my colleague for 30 years
私の30年来の同僚です
Actually, I just entered Academia Sinica
実は私は中央研究院に入学したばかりです
Has been in Academia Sinica for 30 years
中央研究院に30年間在籍
So
それで
when i first came in
初めて来たとき
when a child comes in
子供が入ってきたとき
At that time, Mr. Chen was already
その時、陳さんはすでに
Madam save life
マダム、命を救ってください
Mr Chen is a
チェンさんは、
An example of successful self-study
独学で成功した例
he in 1955
1955年の彼
Entered Academia Sinica after graduating from high school
高校卒業後、中央研究院に入学
so he is very few
だから彼はとても少ない
Among the colleagues we are familiar with now
私たちが今よく知っている同僚の中には
Worked with Dean Hu
ディーン・フーと仕事をした
so used to
とても慣れています
Mr. Chen also told me
陳さんも言ってました。
Dean Hu follows this
ディーン・フーがこれをフォロー
meeting of academicians
学者の会合
There are many inside stories about conflicts with President Chiang
蒋介石総統との数々の対立の内幕
he was there
彼はそこにいました
So he is a very senior colleague
だから彼はとても先輩の同僚です
He later worked in the Department of History
彼は後に歴史学科で働きました
After graduating from the National Taiwan University Institute of Archeology
国立台湾大学考古学研究所卒業後
So officially become a researcher
それで正式に研究者になる
but it is important that he
しかし重要なのは彼が
He is the assistant of Mr. Li Ji, the chief teacher of the third group of archeology
彼は考古学第3グループの主任教師である李吉氏の助手です。
So he, a senior in archaeology who came into contact with
そこで彼は、考古学の先輩であり、
Much
非常多
Then after the 1980s
そして1980年代以降
He changed from Taiwan
彼は台湾から変わりました
and marine island archeology
海洋島考古学
In Taipei County, Nantou County, Pingdong County, Hualien County, Taitung County, Kinmen County, Lianjiang County
台北県、南投県、平東県、花蓮県、台東県、金門県、連江県
has his important archaeological discoveries
彼の重要な考古学的発見がある
Everyone, if you go to Puri, there is a site called Qubing
みなさん、プリに行くとQubingというサイトがあります
I remember that this site also presents this
このサイトでも紹介されていたと記憶しています
The Bibing Site in Puri is now also a place to visit
プリのビビング・サイトも訪れるべき場所になりました
So next time you go, you can pay a little attention
じゃあ次に行くときはちょっと気を付けてみようかな
But more importantly, he discovered this 8,000-year-old historical record in Matsu three years ago.
しかし、もっと重要なことは、彼が3年前に馬祖でこの8,000年の歴史的記録を発見したことです。
Liangdao Ruins in the New Era
新時代の梁島遺跡
with two islanders
島民二人と
present this daily research
この日々の研究を発表します
More professional research and less teaching in China
中国では専門的な研究が増え、教育は減りました
But he was also in Thailand
でも彼もタイにいました
Xi Jinping University and Xiamen University have been visiting professors
習近平大学とアモイ大学が客員教授を招聘
He is also a member of the Art Center for Chinese Archaeological Research at the Chinese University of Hong Kong.
彼は香港中文大学の中国考古学研究芸術センターのメンバーでもあります。
Honorary Research Fellow, Jianqiao University and University of California, Random Seven
建橋大学およびカリフォルニア大学ランダムセブン名誉研究員
And visiting scholars at the University of Arizona, the Department of Anthropology, etc.
そしてアリゾナ大学人類学部などの客員学者たち。
I think his efforts are very admirable
彼の努力はとても素晴らしいと思う
especially after he retires
特に彼が引退した後は
There is another important discovery that I find very rare
非常に珍しいと思われるもう一つの重要な発見があります
So now we welcome him with a round of applause
だから今、私たちは彼を拍手で歓迎します
associate dean
副院長
The incumbent Yang county magistrate
現職の陽県判事
Many colleagues in our institute
私たちの研究所にはたくさんの仲間がいます
advanced
先進
many my neighbors
私の多くの隣人
my friend
私の友人
And many friends outside our hospital
そして病院の外にもたくさんの友人がいます
what a great honor today
今日はなんて光栄なことでしょう
I have the opportunity to report my recent work to the chairman
最近の仕事を会長に報告する機会があります
It has been fourteen years since Chen Rou Fuyuan talked about the special break
チェン・ロウ・フユアンが特別な休暇について語ってから14年が経ちました
i have to do it again
もう一度やらなければなりません
So here are four opportunities
ここに 4 つのチャンスがあります
I'm thinking
考えています
This is the Central Research Institute
こちらは中央研究所です
I went from technician to researcher
技術者から研究者になりました
Well actually like
まあ、実際には好きです
knowledge miss this
知識はこれを見逃します
This presentation is actually a dream of our researchers.
実はこの発表は研究者たちの夢でした。
because we know
私たちは知っているから
There are only four liberal arts students a year
文系学生は1学年に4名しかいない
There are thousands of people in our research institute
私たちの研究所には何千人もの人々がいます
so i have a chance
だから私にはチャンスがある
Is to become the deputy dean's outsider
副学部長の部外者となる
schedule this presentation
このプレゼンテーションをスケジュールする
and all that I'm going to talk about today
そして今日私が話すことすべて
story
話
nonstop story
ノンストップストーリー
this story
この話
this is good
これはいい
There are so many links that link each other
相互にリンクするリンクがたくさんあります
Missing a link Our success rate
リンクがありません 当社の成功率
will not have a good success rate
成功率は良くないでしょう
this so slowly let me come
ゆっくり行かせてください
i think we forgot one thing
私たちは一つ忘れていたと思う
i just forgot one thing
一つだけ忘れてしまいました
I have a gift for Yang Xianchang
ヤン・シアンチャンにプレゼントがあります
This gift can currently be opened without first opening
このギフトは現在、最初に開封しなくても開封できます
because wait a minute there will be
ちょっと待ってください。
show something
何かを見せます
Am I the vice president now, please?
私は今副社長ですか？
Did I give it to him myself?
私自身が彼にあげたのですか？
That's calligraphy on clothes
それは服に描かれたカリグラフィーです
but you have one of my poems
でもあなたは私の詩を一つ持っています
wait a minute i will introduce
ちょっと待ってください、紹介します
Our topic for this story today is
今日のこの話のテーマは、
Archaeological treasures of Cliff Mountain
クリフ・マウンテンの考古学的宝物
The story of the 8,000-year-old Ryoshima people
8,000年前の両島人の物語
I divide five stories
5つのストーリーに分かれています
Let's look at the following
以下を見てみましょう
First of all, what I want to introduce is to ask
まず最初にご紹介したいのは、
Any ladies and gentlemen who have been to Matsu raise your hands please
松に行ったことのある皆様手を挙げてください
Wow so much
すごいね
I watched half of it
半分くらい見ました
very good very good thank you thank you
とても良い とても良い ありがとう ありがとう
This Mazu is really the one that Dean Fu mentioned just now.
この媽祖こそが、先ほどディーン・フーが言った媽祖そのものなのです。
It's a beautiful scenery
美しい景色ですね
does not belong to greek love sea does not belong to mediterranean
ギリシャの愛の海に属さない 地中海に属さない
So where are the two islands?
それで、その二つの島はどこにあるのでしょうか？
It is the location between Beigang and Dongying, which is 27 kilometers away.
北港と東営の間の場所で、距離は27キロです。
I'll talk about its importance in a moment
その重要性については後ほどお話します
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
So this is the two islands
これが 2 つの島です
to some seaside many in Matsu
馬祖のどこかの海辺へ
This island is all of this flower dry rock structure
この島はすべてこの花の乾いた岩の構造物です
let's look at these
これらを見てみましょう
look again
もう一度見てください
we can see this
私たちはこれを見ることができます
That view is all mainland fishing boats
その景色はすべて本土の漁船です
That's the mainland
それが本土だ
Looking west from here is the mainland
ここから西を見ると本土です
let's take a look
見てみましょう
Its shellfish are of course island shellfish
貝類はもちろん島貝です
Mostly herbaceous
主に草本
few woody plants
木本植物が少ない
But there are also paper vines that are good plants
しかし、紙の蔓も良い植物です
let's take a look
見てみましょう
This is also a characteristic of Mazu
これも媽祖の特徴です
migratory bird of its seabird season
海鳥の季節の渡り鳥
When they arrive they have apotheosis
彼らが到着すると神格化が得られます
Empty end fit
空嘴端配合
this tern
このアジサシ
we look good
私たちは良いようです
that's what tern means
それがアジサシの意味です
Mainland fishing boats often fish there
本土の漁船がよくそこで漁をし​​ます。
we look good
私たちは良いようです
This is the first story
これが最初の話です
how to tell the first story
最初のストーリーをどう伝えるか
the first story says
最初の話は言う
The Liangdao archaeological site is reserved for those who are destined
良島遺跡は運命の人のために予約されています
how do you say this
どのようにこれを言うのですか
Let's go back to the map just now
先ほどの地図に戻りましょう
that map
その地図
That map just now
たった今のその地図
right
右
The location of Liangdao is because it is between Beigang and Dongying
梁島の位置は北港と東営の間にあるためです。
When our two sides are facing each other
私たちの二つの側面が向かい合うとき
its positional importance
その位置的重要性
If this island is not guarded by our national army
この島が国軍に守られなかったら
This cold line will be cut
この冷たいラインは切断されます
will be cut off
切られるだろう
let's see and go back
見て帰りましょう
when is this island
この島はいつですか
It was the first time that the national army boarded to occupy this island
国軍がこの島を占領するために乗り込んだのは初めてだった
Because it was an uninhabited island
無人島だったので
In fact, this island is no stranger to the Matsu people.
実はこの島は馬祖族にとって見知らぬ島ではありません。
Mount Heng in ancient times
古代の恒山
it is no stranger
それは見知らぬ人ではありません
Also like the fishermen of Daegu Island in Kitaoka
北岡の大邱島の漁師たちも好き
Now many fishermen are talking
今、多くの漁師たちが話しています。
The fisheries there are very rich
そこの漁業はとても豊かです
go fishing there
そこで釣りに行く
very strange
非常に奇妙な
But because of its importance when cross-strait confrontation
しかし、海峡を越えた対立の際にはそれが重要であるため、
so then what
それで、それでは何ですか
When was this called and changed it to Langdao
これがいつ呼ばれてLangdaoに変更されたのか
The waves of the waves we don't know
僕らの知らない波の波
no way
とんでもない
That's July 15, 1951
それは1951年7月15日のことです
At that time the national army
当時の国軍は
We now call it the National Army
今では国軍と呼んでいます
It's actually called the National Salvation Army
正式には救世軍といいます。
That is a force army of Emperor Fan
それは樊皇帝の軍隊です
He has a Captain Li Chengshang
彼には李承尚大尉がいる
led six landowners
6人の地主を率いて
Seven people went up to plant the flag
7人が旗を立てるために上がった
After that we will occupy the island
その後、島を占領します
But at that time, because of the supply, the island
しかし当時、物資の都合で島は
very difficult
非常困難
It is very difficult to replenish Lulu Deficiency
路路虛虛補給非常困難
so sometimes there is occupation
だから時々職業があります
sometimes there is no way
時には方法がありません
just wait
ちょっと待って
until 1965
1965年まで
It was confirmed that a group of troops went up
部隊が登頂したのが確認された
But in 1966
しかし1966年に
At that time Chiang Ching-kuo
当時の蔣経国
when he was the secretary of homeland security
彼が国土安全保障長官だったとき
he changed the name
彼は名前を変えた
He thinks it is the island standing in the sky that shines on the mainland
彼は本土に輝く空に浮かぶ島だと思っている
So change to Liangdao
それで梁島に乗り換えます
The name was changed at that time
その時に名前が変わりました
Then in 2011
そして2011年に
At that time there was a commemorative meeting on the island
その時島では記念集会があった
60th anniversary commemoration
創立60周年記念
I'll tell his story later
彼の話は後で話します
Let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
at this time
現時点では
because of this commemoration
この記念のせいで
You just invited Li Chengshang for this cup
あなたはこのカップに李成尚を招待しました
The original team members are now among the seven
元のチームメンバーは現在 7 名に含まれています
Now there are only two left
これで残りは2つだけになりました
He was invited to attend this meeting
彼はこの会議に出席するよう招待された
Go and see what the island is like now
島が今どうなっているのか見に行ってください
when
いつ
County Magistrate Yang invited by him
楊県判事が彼に招待された
County Magistrate Yang also went up
楊県判事も出廷
also when going up
上がるときも
County Magistrate Yang is a county magistrate with very good humanistic qualities
ヤン郡判事は、非常に優れた人間性を備えた郡判事です。
He has been on this island for sixty years
彼はこの島に60年間住んでいます
In fact, in 1965, when a large number of our troops went up
実際、1965 年に多数の軍隊が蜂起したとき、
In fact he drove that way and said
実際、彼はそこへ車を運転してこう言いました。
In fact it's hard
実際、それは難しいです
open that road
その道を開けてください
That chair should have sections cut out
その椅子には部分が切り取られているはずです
should have appeared then
その時現れるべきだった
But until 60 years later
でも60年後まで
Our county magistrate Yang went up to see
私たちの県判事ヤンが様子を見に行った
Oops, this is a back seed
おっと、これは裏シードです
just notify me to investigate
私に知らせて
That's why I found this chair
そこでこの椅子を見つけました
Let's look at the next one
次を見てみよう
Then the shape of the guide is like this
するとガイドの形状はこんな感じです
That little red dot in the north
北にあるあの小さな赤い点
near the first position
最初の位置付近
first position
最初の位置
The port that County Magistrate Yang went to is called Baisheng Port
楊県令が行った港は白盛港と呼ばれています
Baishenggang, the back breed he looked at when he went up
彼が登ったときに見た後ろの品種、白生崗
that's the place
それが場所です
Later we saw that it was a chair from the Ming and Qing Dynasties
後でわかったのですが、それは明清時代の椅子でした。
that hand
那那手
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
this is history
これは歴史です
we don't know
私たちは知りません
friend of this guide
このガイドの友人
say
言う
Mr. Chen Yiyong gave it to me
チェン・イーヨンさんが私にくれました
then it will be difficult
それなら難しいだろう
March 1965
1965年3月
Only when we officially have a large force can we go up
公式に大きな軍隊を持った場合にのみ、私たちは上に上がることができます
Just put this army in the emperor
この軍隊を皇帝の中に入れてください
Formal and discreet emperor
形式的かつ控えめな天皇
That's when I took the second picture
その時に2枚目の写真を撮りました
Pay attention to see that the equipment of their troops cannot be compared with today's
彼らの軍隊の装備は今日のものとは比較できないことに注意してください。
it was very very hard
とてもとても大変でした
I am in this six years
私はこの6年間にいます
when i was in the army
私が軍隊にいたとき
It was very hard back then
当時はとても大変でした
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
This is after going up from Baishenggang
こちらは白勝港から上がったところです
This place has a Xiaoliang Pavilion
この場所には小涼閣があります
That is the Ming and Qing Dynasties
それが明と清の時代です
In the back that County Magistrate Yang saw
ヤン県判事が見たその裏側
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
This is the first time I've been
行ったのは今回が初めてです
When I climbed up, I was talking about the fact that there are
登ったときに、あるという話をしていました。
Both have this back phenomenon and back phenomenon
どちらもこの裏現象と裏現象がある
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
i have a poe
私はポーを持っています
This is the back
こちらは裏側です
Actually this back
実はこの背中
But because there are several floors piled up on the road
でも道路に何階も重なっているので
not the original
オリジナルではない
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
When we first went to investigate
私たちが初めて調査に行ったとき
we see this
私たちはこれを見ます
This is driving the road
これは道路を運転しています
it cuts the section
それはセクションをカットします
so i see this
だから私はこれを見ます
After this back becomes 50 centimeters
この後背が50センチになります
30 meters long
長さ30メートル
all terrible
すべてひどい
I later I will
後でそうします
Let's go inside it first
まずは中に入ってみましょう
because we all know
私たちは皆知っているから
so-called back seeding
いわゆるバックシード
Ashes may occur because the back becomes
背面になりますので灰が発生する場合がございます
natural disaster
自然災害
natural
天然的
those climates what death
あの気候は死とは何か
may occur
発生する可能性があります
That can't be called being planted
それは植えられたとは言えません
so-called archaeological species
いわゆる考古学的種
It must be human food waste
それは人間の食品廃棄物に違いない
throw the husk there
そこに殻を投げる
Because there are people in the abdomen
お腹に人がいるから
Many of our cultural relics are thrown inside
私たちの文化的遺物の多くが内部に投げ込まれています
The broken nets that escaped everywhere were thrown away in there
あちこちに逃げた破れた網はそこに捨てられていた
That's why we call it seeded
それがシードと呼ばれる理由です
we're together we're a team
私たちは一緒です、私たちはチームです
four of us go up
私たち4人は上ります
Let's just say I looked at that pottery
私がその陶器を見たとしましょう
i was startled
私はびっくりした
Even the sons of Taiwan left without him
台湾の息子たちも彼を残して去った
looks like
のように見える
so let's see the next one
それでは次を見ましょう
The most important thing is that when I investigate
最も重要なことは、調査するときに
The most important thing is this one of us
最も重要なことは私たちのうちの一人です
Now he is the curator of the Matsu Folklore Cultural and Military Museum
現在は馬祖民俗資料館学芸員。
Mr. Pan Jianguo
潘建國先生
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
Where is he
彼はどこにいますか
As soon as I say we are
私たちがいると言うとすぐに
bottom layer
最下層
We all dig a little bit of this back
みんなでこれを少し掘り下げてみましょう
Cut the peach slices if you can
できれば桃をスライスしてください
go back and make specimens
戻って標本を作ります
let's check
確認しよう
For example, when he digs the back
たとえば、彼が背中を掘るとき、
He dug up the two sides
彼は両面を掘り起こした
Three pieces in total
合計3枚
He showed me he said it was weird
彼はそれが奇妙だと言っているのを私に見せた
why is this so thin
なぜこれはそんなに薄いのですか
I can't see it
見えない
this is a human skull
これは人間の頭蓋骨です
so i immediately
だから私はすぐに
I'll hug the plastic bag quickly
すぐにビニール袋を抱きしめるよ
I said this place
この場所って言いました
cover it up
それを覆い隠す
I will invite the captain of the army
軍の隊長を招待します
Captain Zhang now has Lieutenant Colonel Shao Xiaosheng
チャン大尉にはシャオ・シャオシェン中佐が就任
What about him
彼についてはどうですか
I said hurry up and try to find a way to make it
私は急いでそれを作る方法を見つけようと言いました
this one
これです
You get a plastic sheet or something to cover the bag
ビニールシートか何かでバッグを覆う
I must come to work again
また仕事に来なければなりません
that this is the first time
これが初めてだということ
Bright leads to discovery of human skull
人間の頭蓋骨の明るい鉛を発見
that's how i found it
それが私がそれを見つけた方法です
This, this, curator Pan, is there to pick
これ、これ、キュレーターのパンが選んでくれます
I said I can't pick anymore
もう選べないって言った
just before
直前
ok let's read the next chapter
はい、次の章を読みましょう
Okay, this second story is
さて、２つ目のお話は、
On the cliff, the fields are surrounded by flowers
崖の上の野原は花に囲まれています
I'm probably going to tell you about the discovery of this plum group.
おそらくこの梅群の発見についてお話しするつもりです。
Bright Island Blossoms
ブライトアイランドブロッサムズ
His cultural background is also Liangdao Neng No. 1 massive brother
彼の文化的背景も梁島能のナンバーワンの巨漢です。
I mistakenly called it Brother Hailiang
間違えて海良兄弟と呼んでしまった
Maybe Brother Hailiang in the future
将来的には海良兄弟になるかもしれない
How is it better educated than his number one
彼のナンバーワンよりもどのように教育が優れているのでしょうか
maybe more colloquial
もっと口語的なかもしれない
Let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
ok at this point we'll decide
わかりました、この時点で決めます
It's cold at this time
寒いです
it is this time
それは今回です
it's cold in december
12月は寒いです
then we will
それなら私たちはそうします
This bed is not going
このベッドは行かない
The cot doesn't leave
ベビーベッドが離れない
very stormy
非常に嵐が多い
we must go up
私たちは登らなければなりません
what to do after that
その後どうするか
county government our county magistrate
郡政府 私たちの郡判事
a lift
リフト
This is probably archeology
これはおそらく考古学です
I am afraid that archeology in Taiwan is the first
残念ながら台湾の考古学は初めてです。
In summer, I also want to be a senior machine
私も夏には上級機になりたいです
this is probably the first time
おそらくこれが初めてです
this at the airport
これは空港で
Shi Lingguang
石陵光
Called back now
今折り返し電話しました
The director of the battle department is now
現在、戦闘部門の部長は
Dean of Brigade Students
旅団学生部長
he sent us this
彼は私たちにこれを送ってくれた
We are going to measure
測定してみます
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
The following is the video
以下はビデオです
Let's just say
言ってみよう
Let's take a look
見てみましょう
this our this
これは私たちのこれ
senior machine
シニアマシン
it's been a long time
おひさしぶりですね
The video is relatively long, I fried it into
動画は比較的長いので、まとめてみました
30 seconds a few seconds
30秒、数秒
Just look at this guide
このガイドを見てください
the form is like this
フォームはこんな感じです
This is
これは
It's this senior aircraft landing pad
これは上級航空機の着陸パッドです
senior airport
シニア空港
There is a road in the middle
真ん中に道があります
actually the central road
実は中央道路
What about the plane?
飛行機はどうですか？
When it gets there first it flies around first
最初にそこに着くと、最初に飛び回る
land after one lap
1周して着地する
Here's a clip of us sitting on the senior plane
これは上級機に座っている私たちのクリップです
this is where we are
ここが私たちのいる場所です
I just forgot to introduce
ただ紹介するのを忘れてました
We also have members of Liangdao archaeological team here.
ここには梁島考古学チームのメンバーもいます。
Taken by Mr. Yin Yizhi
撮影：イン・イージ氏
This amount of island is like this
この量の島はこんな感じ
just such a small island
とても小さな島です
very small island
非常小的一個島
Only 0.37 square kilometers
わずか0.37平方キロメートル
We are sitting on the senior plane in this plane
私たちはこの飛行機の上級機に座っています
we went first
私たちが最初に行きました
Now we're slowly descending
今はゆっくりと下降中です
don't land
着陸しないでください
one of the following videos
次のビデオのいずれか
because when we can
なぜなら、できるときは
Let's go first and get the full
まずはいっぱい食べてみましょう
where are we going to work
私たちはどこで働きますか
let's test it first
まずはテストしてみましょう
At this time our tool
現時点での私たちのツール
Only gold luck left
残るは金運だけ
We have nineteen boxes of tools
私たちは工具の入った箱を19個持っています
I packed a family of small fish boats with a scoop
小さな漁船の家族にスコップを詰め込んだ
just go up
ただ上がってください
you can watch it roar
あなたはそれが轟音を立てるのを見ることができます
wait a minute to see
ちょっと待って見てください
This fella Bin
このビン君
how do they go at this pier
彼らはこの桟橋をどうやって行くのですか
almost every time
ほぼ毎回
Three or two days a scoop boat
スコップ船で3日か2日
one scoop boat a week
週に 1 本のスクープボート
His carrier says they all have to work so hard
彼の運送業者は、全員が一生懸命働かなければならないと言っています
this pier is
この桟橋は
The current military light is very, very difficult
現在の軍用照明は非常に困難です
the vice captain
副船長
The captain without the vice-captain is the leader
副船長のいない船長がリーダーとなる
The vice-captain is going to fight
副船長が戦います
to play forward
前向きにプレーする
all on top
すべてが上にある
We are affected by the sea less often
私たちは海の影響を受けることが少なくなります
in this way
この上
This is our pregnant stuff
これが私たちの妊娠中のものです
business case
ビジネスケース
The second is Mayor Fukushima
二人目は福島市長です
David Fukushima
デビッド・フクシマ
so now
だから今
Now the army has to be born first
さて、まず軍隊を誕生させなければならない
very hard
とても厳しい
This one is wearing black and this one is the vice-captain
この人は黒を着ています、そして、この人は副キャプテンです
Captain was not on the island at that time
その時船長は島にいなかった
Thanks
ありがとう
So go through the plug
それでプラグを通します
we're afraid things will be missed
私たちは物事が見逃されるのではないかと心配しています
You can see them all
それらすべてを見ることができます
Here
ここ
Fighting against the waves
波との戦い
Okay, thank you
大丈夫ありがとう
let's go on
続けましょう
ok then we are on the next one
わかりました、それでは次の作業に進みます
This is luck
これは幸運です
Then when we start going up
それから登り始めると
Later we were here again
その後、私たちは再びここに来ました
we found the second place
私たちは2番目の場所を見つけました
Third place
第三地
Fourth place Third place
4位 3位
We later found four more locations
その後、さらに 4 か所の場所が見つかりました
Of course the first location is the best
もちろん最初の場所が最高です
is the earliest
一番早いです
second a little later
2番目は少し後で
The second location is more than 7,000 years old
2位は樹齢7000年以上
this is the second place
これは2番目の場所です
The situation at the second location
2箇所目の現場の様子
this can be seen
これは見える
The back of the city piled here, the back of the master
ここに積み重なった街の裏側 マスターの裏側
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
This is the so-called backmaster
いわゆるバックマスターです
piled up here
ここに積まれている
here are some
ここにあるいくつかの
This is a stone tool
これは石器です
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
At this time we are digging
現時点では掘削中です
So we're on this cliff
だから私たちはこの崖の上にいるのです
only this rope
このロープだけ
Then our rope
それから私たちのロープ
who dares to work on it
誰がそれに取り組む勇気があるか
the military said
軍は言った
All you soldiers, you go up
兵士の皆さん、上がってください
Just wear a belt around your waist
腰にベルトを巻くだけ
Hook the hook on this rope lock
このロープロックにフックを引っ掛けます
I said it's not okay
大丈夫じゃないって言った
Neither can our people
私たちの人々もそうすることはできません
Wear a belt every day
毎日ベルトを着用してください
what to do
何をすべきか
Quickly, the military added three lines to form a net
軍はすぐに3本の線を追加して網を形成した
this is much safer
これははるかに安全です
Then this lady originally Suppose
それからこの女性はもともと
Shouldn't just wear protective clothing
防護服を着るだけではいけない
Because why are you looking for protective clothing?
なぜ防護服を探しているのですか？
because we are afraid
私たちは怖いから
This is also our first archeology in Taiwan
これは台湾での最初の考古学でもあります
We are afraid that when we go to dig up this human bone
私たちはこの人骨を掘り出すとき、
we will pollute that
私たちはそれを汚してしまいます
DNA from that skeleton
その骸骨からのDNA
In the future, DNA will say pollution
将来、DNAは汚染を言うだろう
inaccurate
不正確な
For example, if it's my bunny girl
例えば私のバニーガールなら
i'm talking now
私は今話しています
Running out is someone Chen's DNA
走り出すのはチェンのDNAだ
no joke
冗談抜き
right
右
So we prepared 20 sets of protective clothing
そこで防護服を20セット用意しました
It's so cold that the temperature is only 6 degrees to 8 degrees
とても寒いので気温は6度から8度しかありません
Digging on this side of this cliff
この崖のこちら側を掘っています
unbearably cold
耐えられないほど寒い
So put on a set of protective clothing first
だから最初に防護服を着てください
this is such a story
これはそんな話です
Then we'll have to plug all the lone walkers we dug up.
それから、掘り出した孤独なウォーカーをすべて接続する必要があります。
our measurement
私たちの測定
field survey
現地測量
this
これ
this hot pit
このホットピット
our location
私たちの場所
it's all on a cliff
すべては崖の上にある
so the topic
それで話題は
This is not an exaggeration at all
これは決して誇張ではありません
Considerations on the cliff
崖の上での考察
ok let's see what happens next
さて、次に何が起こるか見てみましょう
well this is our job
まあ、これが私たちの仕事です
If this man's skull is dug here
もしこの男の頭蓋骨がここで掘られたら
let's go first
まずは行きましょう
save it here first
まずここに保存してください
Others are pitting us
他の人が私たちに敵対している
main hope not to be shattered
打ち砕かれない主な希望
broken edge
壊れたエッジ
So we dig like this
だから私たちはこのように掘る
Layer by layer
一層一層
This pit is dug layer by layer
この穴は層ごとに掘られています
dug out
掘り出した
stuff up no matter what
何があっても詰め込む
Apple stuffed
リンゴのぬいぐるみ
let's see what happens next
次に何が起こるか見てみましょう
Well, of course there is a lot of congestion.
まあ、当然ですが大混雑です。
We have to pick things out
私たちは物事を選ばなければなりません
After the things are picked out, they need to be classified
物を取り出したら分類する必要がある
still have to take
まだ取らなければならない
go to that
そこに行く
support weight
サポート重量
wrap up
要約
this is me
これが私です
I have to work too
私も働かなければなりません
well watch the next one
まあ次を見てください
This is unearthed pottery
こちらは出土した土器です
Many of these pottery pieces are scientific and cultural
これらの陶器の多くは科学的かつ文化的なものです
Of course there are many of them and Zi Jiawen
もちろん、それらの多くはありますが、Zi Jiawen
Violet Gavin
バイオレット・ギャビン
according to these things
これらのことによると
and this cabbage
そしてこのキャベツ
so a little bit
だから少し
So it's Kushidai only from
なのでクシダイのみです。
probably at the earliest
おそらく早いうちに
Because our strata did the first time Taiwan University did it in 7900
台湾大学が私たちの編成で初めてそれをやったのは7900年だったからです
the earliest should be
最も早いはずです
This formation is 7900 years old
この地層は7900年前のものです
But the human bones are under this layer
しかし、人間の骨はこの層の下にあります
So it's earlier 8300 to 8000 a
つまり、8300から8000まで早いです
such a formation
そのようなフォーメーション
Then the above point is about 7500
すると上記のポイントは約7500になります
This stratum is like this
この地層はこんな感じ
let's look at the next level
次のレベルを見てみましょう
This is the lover of its pottery
これは陶器の愛好家です
its sherds
その破片
this is a harpoon
これは銛です
What about the harpoon?
銛はどうですか？
it this harpoon is a thrown harpoon
この銛は投げられた銛です
after throwing it out
吐き出した後
There's a small harpoon in the back
後ろに小さな銛がある
this rope
このロープ
Most are broken
ほとんどが壊れています
why?
なぜ？
the fish broke
魚が壊れた
the rest of the head
頭の残りの部分
we can see below
以下で見ることができます
This is a complete harpoon
これは完全な銛です
In our Yangxian long special preference
私たちの陽県の長い特別な好みでは
We will hold the national treasure in the future
国宝を将来も保有します
Qingnian
大清年
chicken vertebrae of this fish
この魚の鶏の脊椎
bone
骨
bone needle
骨針
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
Its stone tools are more primitive
石器はより原始的です
In fact, the traces of typing are not very clear.
実際のところ、タイプした跡はあまり鮮明ではありません。
Mostly sourced locally
ほとんどが地元で調達されている
Because why do we call it a stone tool
なぜ石器と呼ぶのか
because it has this tall trace
この高いトレースがあるから
through usable stone
使える石を通して
To become a stone tool
石器になる
what can be made
何が作れるのか
this blade cloth
この刃布
Damaged loss by all use
あらゆる使用による損害損失
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
Thanks
ありがとう
At this time, we discovered that we found here
今回、ここで発見したのは、
we keep it covered
私たちはそれをカバーしておきます
we keep this piece
私たちはこの部分を保管します
At this time we have a thought
このとき私たちには考えがあります
just don't know
ただ知らないだけ
i know the human skull is in this place
人間の頭蓋骨がこの場所にあることは知っています
After all, the human body was dug out
結局人体は掘り出された
has been dug up
掘り起こされた
Still hiding in this stick
まだこの棒の中に隠れている
So let's just keep this one
じゃあこれだけにしておきましょう
After the above is cleaned up
上記をクリーンアップした後、
Let's get back to the stick problem
スティックの問題に戻りましょう
So I slowly cleared up this part
だからこそ、この部分をゆっくりとクリアしていきました
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
Clear it out and dig it down slowly
撤去してゆっくり掘り下げていきます
It's such a level
そんなレベルだよ
It turns out that reproduction is inside
中には生殖機能があることが判明
it's the rod of exorcism
それは悪魔祓いの杖です
I have another story to tell at this point
この時点でもう一つ話したいことがあります
because we found out later
後でわかったから
I will ask
聞いてみます
Friends of Fuguo Bingyu
フグオ・ビンギュの友達
Do you have any I want to hear their stories
彼らの話を聞きたいのはありますか
An instructor who is still in Huanian High School
現在も華安高校に在籍中の講師
Lieutenant Colonel Qin Huaian
秦淮安中佐
He said that long ago his Abbiers kissed the head of the side
彼は昔、彼のアビンスがサイドの頭にキスをしたと言った
once dug up the human bones of three sentences
かつて三文の人骨を掘り出したことがある
Two sentences are for adults and one sentence is for children and babies
2 つの文は大人向け、1 つの文は子供と赤ちゃん向けです
An adult kneels like this
大人はこうやってひざまずく
He suspected that at that time it was probably the old Communist
彼は、当時それはおそらく古い共産主義者だったのではないかと疑った。
So those people are kneeling and pushed into the sea
だからあの人たちはひざまずいて海に突き落とされている
So this is destined, chairman
これは運命ですね、会長
Do you think if he found out then
もしその時彼が知っていたらと思いますか
Then it won't be our turn
そうなると私たちの番ではなくなります
Such
そのような
good
良い
Then when we dig out this curiosity
そして、この好奇心を掘り起こしてみると、
I will delete it with our team
私たちのチームで削除します
I said it's so cold
とても寒いと言いました
If this thing is cleared up now
これで問題が解決すれば
all each
それぞれのすべて
The bones must be broken and broken, and so early
骨が折れて折れるのは早いですね
I said we better ship it back
送り返したほうがいいと言いました
this can't move now
これはもう動けない
And once this is cleared up
そしてこれがクリアされたら
able to flash
フラッシュできる
There is no way to look like you can
できるように見える方法はありません
there's no way you can't fight back
反撃できないわけがない
OK, we decided to dig
OK、掘ることにしました
So just dig a piece
だからちょっと掘ってみよう
wrap it up
急いでください
After wrapping it up we dig
巻き終わったら掘ってみます
Dig a piece and transport it back to Nangan
一部を掘って南竿に持ち帰る
Folklore Museum to deal with slowly
ゆっくりと向き合う民俗資料館
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
this time is very difficult
今回はとても難しいです
except outside digging at the bottom
底部の外側の掘削を除く
You have to dig out the set list first and put it in first.
まずセットリストを掘り起こして、それを最初に組み込む必要があります。
to be able to drag the whole thing out
全体を引きずり出すことができる
So we wrap it tight and just do it
だから私たちはそれをしっかりと包み込んで、ただそれを行うだけです
Pull it out and put it in the box later
取り出して後で箱に入れます
transport it back to nangan
南竿まで運ぶ
let's take a look
見てみましょう
Zhuanxiang
伝祥
Oh, this boat came back to Nangang
ああ、この船は南港に帰ってきた
just shipped it back
ちょうど送り返したところです
ok let's see below
さて、以下を見てみましょう
Oh, this is about the third
あ、これで3つ目くらいです
This Liangdao man
この梁島の男
Fortunately, Brother Hailiang belongs to Heshui people
幸いなことに、海良兄弟は合水族の出身です。
his age
他的年代
how do we guess
どうやって推測しますか
Just pull his sleeping rib
寝ている肋骨を引っ張るだけ
make carbon stone firm
カーボンストーンをしっかりさせる
So guess it is
そうだと思います
He is the BG of plus or minus 40 years in 738
738年プラスマイナス40年のBGです
His because of correction
彼の矯正のため
All carbon stones must be calibrated
すべてのカーボンストーンは校正する必要があります
The correction result is 8320 to 8060
補正結果は8320～8060
BP on B4 Pleasant
B4 の BP プレザント
is huge gold
巨大な金です
is modern
現代的です
Ten years old is around 8300 to 8300
10歳は8300～8300くらい
His inspection of us. This is the third paragraph we are going to talk about.
彼の私たちへの視察 これがこれからお話しする 3 番目の段落です。
ok, let's see
さて、まず以下を見てみましょう
Oh, this one is back at the Matsu Literary and Art Museum
あ、これは馬祖文学美術館に戻ってきました。
let's see next
次に見てみましょう
his clean up
彼の掃除
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
this time we start
今度は始めます
just find another team
別のチームを見つけてください
As for Dr. Qiu Honglin from the Institute of Anthropology of Tsinghua University
清華大学人類学研究所の邱紅林博士については
he is an assistant professor
彼は助教授です
He came to clean the bone
彼は骨をきれいにするために来た
he slowly cleans up
彼はゆっくりと掃除をする
I rented this dirt and slowly peeled it off
この汚れを借りてゆっくり剥がしてみた
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
This is what it looks like when you peel it off
剥がすとこんな感じです
It's all a phenomenon of driving obstacles
それはすべて障害物を運転する現象です
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
At this time we are going to take pictures and draw pictures
今回は写真を撮ったり絵を描いたりする予定です
it is like this
それはこんな感じです
Now, we
ここで私たちは
we are talking about
私たちは〜について話している
let's see next
次に見てみましょう
The picture drawn is like this
描かれた絵はこんな感じ
This is the picture of the car
これは車の写真です
let's see below
以下を見てみましょう
its probably male
それはおそらく男性です
Number 1 is male
1位は男性です
Around 30 years old
30歳くらい
go outside without armor
鎧を着ずに外に出る
no coffin
棺はありません
What about the possession? I didn't find it.
所有物はどうですか? 見つかりませんでした。
Up to the first time
初回まで
each piece is so big
一つ一つの部分がとても大きいので
History of the 20 cm diameter
直径20cmの歴史
it's interesting
それは面白い
Because not long ago we were in
つい最近まで私たちはそこにいたからです
hold an international seminar
国際セミナーを開催する
An archaeologist from Vietnam came
ベトナムから考古学者が来ました
he reports
他報告
from their place
彼らの場所から
There are also a group of district executives
地区幹部のグループもあります
But much more than our time
しかし、私たちの時代よりもはるかに多くの
He said they had a piece of history on their rods
彼は、彼ら全員に歴史の一部があると言いました
There's a piece of history all over it
そこには歴史の一部がある
so is there some connection
それで何か関係があるのですか
we are still doing research
私たちはまだ研究を続けています
what about this person
この人はどうですか
He is not a secondary account for the primary account
彼はプライマリ アカウントのセカンダリ アカウントではありません
lump sum
一時金
the overall performance
全体的なパフォーマンス
Mouth ancient ah
口グー
Everything in this world is more flowery
この世のすべてはもっと花らしく
Spade-shaped incisors are characteristic of Mongolians
鋤形の切歯はモンゴル人の特徴です
in this way
この上
Then he probably because of his dead ancient cut collection
それから彼はおそらく彼の死んだ古代のカットコレクションのせいでした
deeper angle
角度比較深
He was identified as male Xu Zhizhan
男性の徐志珍さんと特定された
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
There's some left
いくつか残っています
Height is about 160 or so
身長は160くらいかな
That
それか
It looks like 158, 160
158、160みたいです
so not very tall
あまり背が高くないので
and some diseases
そしていくつかの病気
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
he marked this
彼はこれに印を付けた
The bones are thicker
骨が太くなる
look at the next one
次を見てください
he has this
彼はこれを持っています
spine
脊椎
have this arthritis problem
この関節炎の問題を抱えている
look at the next one
次を見てください
that has arthritis
関節炎を患っている人
his teeth
彼の歯
This has
これは持っています
just bite
ただ噛むだけ
very that
とてもそれ
Fragrance is very powerful
香りはとても強力です
Eat well
よく食べる
This can be seen
これは見られます
look at the next one
次を見てください
and ears
そして耳
What is the ear type like?
耳のタイプは何ですか？
I'm looking at the next one
次を見ています
modern man
現代人
Filling people's ears
人々の耳を満たす
Hello E.
サーヴァントE
Japanese and Korean divers
日本人と韓国人のダイバー
Those who often dig their backs
よく背中を掘る人
divers
ダイバー
will have this problem
この問題が発生するでしょう
It can be seen that she is often active there
彼女はそこでよく活動していることがわかります
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
when this is done
これが完了したら
The result of the repair is like this
修理結果はこんな感じ
very important point
非常に重要な点
We're going to do 3D image scanning
3D画像スキャンを行っていきます
This is the Cultural Resources Bureau of the Ministry of Culture
こちらは文化省文化資源局です。
Cultural Groups in Tainan
台南の文化グループ
one of its teams came in
そのチームの一つがやって来た
Why not to do 3D scanning
なぜ3Dスキャンをしないのか
because what i just said
なぜなら私が今言ったこと
If we take all the bones
骨を全部取ってしまったら
After opening the glass
グラスを開けた後
you can't fight back
あなたは反撃できません
Current Technology 3D Scanning
現在のテクノロジー 3D スキャン
It's you who made it to this extent
ここまでやり遂げたのはあなたです
I would like to 3D scan after
後で3Dスキャンしたいです
It will be like a printer in the future
将来的にはプリンターのようになるでしょう
Will restore it back later
後で元に戻します
just make a model
ただモデルを作るだけ
rely on this set of technology
この一連のテクノロジーに依存する
So we also made this set of techniques
そこで、この一連のテクニックも作成しました
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
I forgot to say just now
今言い忘れた
all the dots
すべての点
It's their 3D scanning of this layout
このレイアウトの 3D スキャンです
later it will be corrected when
後で修正されます
Rely on this point to correct
この点を頼りに修正してください
because you transform
あなたが変身するから
Sometimes this angle and so on will be deformed
場合によってはこの角度などが変形してしまうこともあります
it may depend on this drug to correct
修正するにはこの薬に依存する可能性があります
now let's see the next one
では次を見てみましょう
The case of this 3D scan
今回の3Dスキャンの事例
Do another 3D scan
もう一度 3D スキャンを実行する
look at the next one
次を見てください
This 3D scan means
この3Dスキャンの意味は、
What I just said is mainly
今言ったことは主に
Reconstructing the circumstances of the burial
埋葬当時の状況を復元する
while doing
しながら
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
The fourth story is
４番目の話は、
Big brother
兄
The Discovery of Massive Girls in "Liangdaoren 2"
「梁道仁2」で大量少女発見
this has many stories
これにはたくさんの物語がある
many stories
たくさんの物語
roughly like this
大体こんな感じ
its discovery was providence
その発見は摂理だった
this is what we are all going to talk about
これが私たち全員が話すことです
how old is it
これはどれくらい古いのですか
Almost 7500-750
ほぼ 7500 ～ 750
This is very accurate
これは非常に正確です
This carbon word is very accurate
このカーボンワードは非常に正確です
this object
このこと
The material difference in the middle is only 30 years
真ん中の物質的な違いはわずか30年です
rather accurate
かなり正確な
Massive girls unearthed suffered setbacks
発掘された大量の少女たちが挫折を経験
She used to be innocent
彼女はかつて無邪気だった
A survey of institutional anthropology
マスシスターシステムの人類学的調査
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
Why is it God's will to say this?
なぜこれを言うのが神の御心なのでしょうか？
when we decided
私たちが決めたとき
When the position of the draped pit is determined
ドレープピットの位置が決まったら
We have two different opinions on the team
チームについては2つの異なる意見がある
One opinion is that
一つの意見としては、
30 meters long from this long
この長さから30メートル
Don't focus too much on here
ここにあまり焦点を当てないでください
you should hit a place where you lose a little
少し負けたところを打ったほうがいい
Then my opinion is don't go too far
それから私の意見は、行き過ぎないことです
Because this place is the last
ここが最後だから
thicker words
分厚い言葉
We may have more things
もっとたくさんのものがあるかもしれない
There are more piles
もっと山があります
that's a compromise
それは妥協だ
As a result, I was 1 meter away from it
その結果、1メートル離れたところにいた
1 meter distance 1 meter
1メートルの距離 1メートル
this is a point
これはポイントです
let's see the next stop
次の停留所を見てみよう
then we have a little more
それならもう少しあります
back to the front
前に戻る
sorry we talked
ごめんなさい、話しました
still think about it
まだそれについて考えています
i think it should be this
これであるべきだと思います
We were originally 1 meter wide
もともと幅は1メートルでした
I should be 1 meter 2
私は1メートル2のはずです
because step aside
なぜなら脇に下がってください
But this side will be a little wider
でもこちら側は少し広くなります
So I think the bigger
だから大きいほうがいいと思います
the bigger the better
大きければ大きいほどいい
So add 20 centimeters to the next stop
だから 20 センチメートル追加して次の停止を観察してください
come out the result
結果が出てくる
yes i didn't show off
はい、自慢しませんでした
we dug this hole
私たちはこの穴を掘りました
It turned out to be here
ここにあることが判明しました
Yes look at this position
はい、この位置を見てください
This came out later
これは後から出てきた
We originally dug the hole here
もともとここに穴を掘っていました
It's almost the end of the digging.
いよいよ掘削も終わりに近づいてきました。
when it's almost over
それがほぼ終わったとき
we are on our feet
私たちは立ち上がっています
its lacquer bone was found
漆の骨が見つかった
So I know that the pit is here
だから私はここに穴があることを知っています
If this place is not clean
ここがきれいじゃなかったら
ignore the paintbone
ペイントボーンを無視する
won't find it either
それも見つからないだろう
Later we dug after the painted bone
その後、ペイントされた骨の後に掘ってみました
we expand
私たちは拡大します
I think it should expand from here
ここから拡張すればいいと思う
That's why I roughly merged them together.
ということでざっくりまとめてみました。
This No. 2 pit looks like this
この第2ピットはこんな感じです
Number two, that's how the second child found out.
2番目に、2番目の子供がそれを知った方法です。
still so easy
まだとても簡単です
what we found
私たちが見つけたもの
If it's us, we won't fight
私たちなら戦わないよ
Wolves won't notice it at all
狼は全然気付かないよ
And if we don't expand a little bit by 20 centimeters
あと20センチくらい広げないと
can't find it either
それも見つからない
This is a very fortunate thing
これはとても幸運なことです
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
alright
大丈夫
The chairman may now find out
会長も今なら分かるかもしれない
There is something wrong with this picture
この写真には何か問題があります
what is the problem
何が問題ですか
its head
その頭
even the bones are gone
骨さえなくなっている
this is a story
これは物語です
Our county magistrate yang is coming
私たちの郡判事ヤンがやって来ます
he will do
彼はやります
he wants to sigh
彼はため息をつきたい
why
なぜ
because we were
私たちがそうだったから
when we dig
私たちが掘るとき
Because there was a typhoon at that time
その時台風が来ていたので
And our teacher Qiu has a class in Tsinghua University
私たちの教師 Qiu は清華大学で授業を行っています
he has no time
彼には時間がない
let's share
共有してみましょう
can't finish this
これを終わらせることはできません
So we found this eyeball
そこで私たちはこの目玉を見つけました
what is this eye socket
この眼窩は何ですか
probably this person looks like
おそらくこの人はこんな感じ
The leg bones look like a little model
脚の骨は小さなモデルのように見えます
We thought we shouldn't dig anymore
私たちはもう掘るべきではないと思った
stop today
今日はやめてください
we'll come back next time
次回また来ます
Do it carefully, there is no time
時間がないので慎重にやってください
another typhoon
別の台風
Let's smoke it back part of the way
途中まで吸って帰ろう
Ma Dong, cover, cover, cover.
マドン、カバー、カバー、カバー。
When we went back last four weeks
過去4週間に戻ったとき
when we started digging
私たちが掘り始めたとき
Oops
おっと
All the bones are gone
骨が全部なくなってしまった
At this time I am very anxious
この時、とても不安です
how do i explain
どう説明すればいいですか
Because everyone can see clearly
誰でもはっきり見えるから
this is heartbreaking
これは悲痛なことです
this is not the old look
これは古い外観ではありません
how to explain this
これをどう説明するか
very urgent
非常急
that's when we thought
そのとき私たちは考えました
there are three possibilities
3つの可能性があります
a man from the sea
海から来た男
One is to bring an occasional person on the island from time to time
一つは、時々島に人を連れてくることです。
The third kind of friendship is that it must be a person who is resident on the island.
3つ目の友情は、その島に住んでいる人でなければならないということです。
There is only Brother Bing on that island
その島にはビング兄弟しかいない
So we make judgments on the spot
だからその場で判断するんだよ
He said it must be from the island
彼はそれは島からのものに違いないと言いました
Do not consider the first two of the three
3 つのうち最初の 2 つは考慮しないでください
people from this island
この島の人々
Because of this, I told the county magistrate
このため、県知事に報告しました。
I said if you change the range from that big
あなたがその大きな範囲から変更するなら、私は言いました
at sea because we were digging
掘っていたので海で
Wearing yellow trousers and changing in vain
黄色いズボンを履いて無駄に着替える
People who assume that the sea is the opposite shore must be curious
海が対岸だと思っている人は気になるでしょうね
I don't know what the hell you're up to, let's go up and see
一体何をしているのか分からない、上がって見に行こう
this is our speculation
これは私たちの推測です
It's impossible for us to say on the spot
その場で言うのは不可能です
must be from the island
島から来ているに違いない
Since I live on the island a lot, we know
私は島によく住んでいるからよく知っている
Harbin and the officers are busy with his business all day and night
ハルビンと役人たちは昼も夜も彼の仕事で忙しい
There is no time left to kill our specimens
標本を殺す時間はもう残されていない
And how can we pull out our face teeth
では、どうすれば顔の歯を抜くことができるのでしょうか？
This is not a medical staff, not familiar with medical treatment
この人は医療従事者ではないので、医療に詳しくありません
People who are familiar with the structure of this human body will only do this kind of thing
この人体の構造を知っている人はこんなことしかしないだろう
We use his on the spot
私たちはその場で彼を使用します
I know, I know
分かった分かった
Then he found it
それから彼はそれを見つけました
found out
見つけた
things are guaranteed
東西也保障
But right now because this is a military guy
でも今は軍隊だから
Still in scouting phase
まだ偵察段階
I can't tell more about his story
彼の話についてはこれ以上話すことはできません
All in all, we got him back as Omi-head
結局のところ、私たちは彼を近江頭として取り戻しました
I only have face to face today
今日は対面しかない
I have the face to say this today
今日はこんなことを言いそうな顔してる
Otherwise I wouldn't be able to do this
そうでなければこんなことはできないだろう
I can't explain this
これは説明できません
This is a very interesting story
これはとても興味深い話です
a story
ストーリー
found it
それを見つけた
Like this, let's see the next one
こんな感じで次も見てみましょう
Probably because of this gender
たぶんこの性別のせいだろう
It was because it hadn't been cleaned up at that time.
その時はまだ掃除がされていなかったからだ。
preliminary resistance
予備抵抗
I thought it was difficult
難しいと思った
It was difficult for us to announce the first time
初めての発表は難しかったです
Then slowly clean him up
それからゆっくりと彼を掃除してください
Plus DNA sent to Germany
さらに DNA をドイツに送信
Because the Germans have these two sentences of DNA
ドイツ人はこれら 2 つの DNA 文を持っているからです
The back skirt of the mitochondria
ミトコンドリアの後部スカート
all appeared
全部現れた
number one is one
1番は1です
I will say later that the second number is 29
2 番目の数字は 29 であると後で言います。
all appeared
全部現れた
Because both sentences are difficult
どちらの文も難しいので
We just want to be a Y chromosome
私たちはただY染色体になりたいだけなのです
Y Narsity DNA減定
Y ナルシティ DNA 減少
As a result, the Germans were number one
結果、ドイツ人が1位になった
do have
確かに持ってます
His DNA has been extracted
彼のDNAは抽出されている
But the second number can't be drawn no matter what
でも2番目の数字はどうやっても引けない
He later tested him and said he was female
その後検査した結果、女性だと言われた
can't be a man
男にはなれない
Later, we consider institutional man as
後で、私たちは制度上の人間を次のように考えます。
The result of this careful examination
この慎重な検査の結果
indeed a woman
まさに女性
So number two we
2番目に私たちは
Correction is female
矯正は女性です
ok let's see below
さて、以下を見てみましょう
And he had a baby
そして彼には赤ちゃんがいました
that lady
あの女性
Then the case of number two
次に、2番目のケースです
He has another one here
彼はここにもう一つ持っています
The stone ball stepped on his feet
石球が彼の足を踏んだ
I don't know if it makes sense
意味があるかどうかはわかりません
do not know either
どちらも知りません
look at the next one
次を見てください
Fu Yuancheng
フー・ユアンチェン
this is really hateful
これは本当に嫌なことだ
Great Faith of Disbelief
忠誠心への不信感
We are still so complete
私たちはまだ完全です
its integrity
その誠実さ
The physical integrity of the entire number two is 85% to 90%
ナンバー 2 全体の物理的完全性は 85% ～ 90% です。
this is machine difficulty
これはマシンの難易度です
it is 7500
7500です
Although it is 7500 years
7500年だけど
but still so complete
しかし、それでも非常に完成度が高い
this is machine difficulty
これはマシンの難易度です
so very happy
とても幸せです
Thanks
ありがとう
look at the next one
次を見てください
This is the comparison of No. 1 and No. 2
こちらはNo.1とNo.2の比較です
you see the face is a little different
顔が少し違うのがわかりますか
the face is a little different
顔が少し違う
look at the next one
次を見てください
these two groups
この2つのグループ
Roughly speaking in the group
グループ内でざっくり言うと
it's very similar
とても似ています
so it should
だからそうすべきだ
this is
これは
is a regional person
地方の人です
On the other hand, number one is male
一方、1位は男性
number two is female
2位は女性です
His face also shows his difference
彼の顔にも違いが表れている
The third is that age is the same
3つ目は、年齢が同じであるということです。
Individuals who are all around 30 years old
全員30歳前後の人たち
height or model situation
身長やモデルの状況
he also has some differences
彼にもいくつかの違いがあります
because of this aspect
この側面のせいで
Today I also have some friends in molecular biology
今日は分子生物学の友達も何人かいます
I am a layman
私は素人です
to teach directly
直接教える
Please teach directly
直接教えてください
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
The comparison of these two sentences is
この 2 つの文を比較すると、
Of course number one and number two are men
もちろん1位と2位は男性です
one is female
一人は女性です
one time at a time
一度に一度
he didn't
彼はしませんでした
are all pits
すべて穴です
none occupied
誰も占有されていない
no coffin
棺はありません
Occupy and no soil hole
占有あり、土穴なし
he is the group
彼はそのグループです
Health group
健康グループ
group like left car
左の車のようなグループ
One is Naozhi
一人はナオジです
two are straight
二人は真っ直ぐです
towards the east
東に向かって
facing one to the left and one to the right
1 つは左を向き、もう 1 つは右を向いて
No training items
トレーニングアイテムはありません
He has the poetry hammer just mentioned.
彼は先ほど言った詩のハンマーを持っています。
Then there is a piece of what I just mentioned
それから、私が今述べたことの一部があります
Is this a sign
これはサインですか
we are still doing research here
私たちはここでまだ研究を続けています
What about number two?
2番はどうでしょうか？
It's a fire pit phenomenon
ファイアーピット現象です
What is the Huotang Phenomenon?
フオタン現象とは何ですか？
there are people from before us
私たちの前から人がいます
used to live here
ここに住んでいた
fire pit and live things
火事場と生き物
was on that spot
その場にいた
I'll be angry later
後で怒られるよ
over there in the garbage dump
あそこのゴミ箱に
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
The results of the DNA analysis
DNA分析の結果
that's because
それは
it's all
それがすべてです
Approaching the modern Austronesian universe
現代のオーストロネシア宇宙に迫る
This Hanshi seat
この範士席
It is similar to the South Island universe
南の島の世界に似ています
high degree of similarity
高い類似性
If the second analysis is reliable
2 番目の分析が信頼できる場合
Daoist Liang may be
梁道士はもしかしたら
linguist preliminary design
言語学者の予備設計
6000 years ago
6000年前
Before the Nandao Yu Clan started phase expansion
Nandao Yu Clanがフェーズ拡張を開始する前
Daoyu Ethnic Group Living in Yuannan, Southeast China
中国南東部元南に住む大宇民族グループ
The result is
結果は
Because its number one is 10,000 to 10,000 haplogroups
一番多いのは 10,000 ～ 10,000 個のハプログループだからです
The second number is haplogroup 290
2 番目の番号はハプログループ 290
It is similar to modern Taiwan, Yuanzhou, America, Philippines
現代の台湾、袁州、アメリカ、フィリピンに似ています
Indonesia, whole Luogang, Southeast Asia
インドネシア、羅港市全域、東南アジア
The Daoyu ethnic group has a matrilineal blood relationship
ダオユ族には母系の血縁関係がある
But now the ethnic groups in the southeast of mainland China
しかし現在、中国本土南東部の民族グループは、
very far from them
彼らからとても遠い
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
This is what I am very cautious about
これは私がとても気をつけていることです
Because in fact the identification of carbon current events
なぜなら、実際には炭素流の現象を特定することができるからです。
We have also done a lot in Taiwan
台湾でもたくさんのことをしてきました
This experience is also very rich
この経験もとても豊かです
For example, National Taiwan University has Guijunshu Experimental Center
たとえば、国立台湾大学には貴君主実験センターがあります。
we first started
私たちが最初に始めたのは
We send him to do whatever we carry
私たちは彼に、私たちが担っているすべてのことをさせるように送ります
very accurate
非常に正確
It's all his 7900
それはすべて彼の 7900 です
that's on his upper floor
そこは彼の上の階にあります
So it's all right
それで大丈夫です
But I'm cautious
でも私は慎重です
We can share the beta that I sent to the United States
私が米国に送ったベータ版を共有できます
That is a very well-known international geography of carbon essence
それは炭素本質に関する非常によく知られた国際地理学です
So there's nothing wrong with taking his own ribs
だから自分の肋骨を取ることは何の問題もない
Because his own bones are made of carbon substance
彼自身の骨は炭素物質でできているため、
The result is
結果は
This is 8320
こちらは8320です
What I just talked about goes all the way to 8160
8160までの話をしました
two sigma
ツーシグマ
Two data come out
データが2つ出てくる
You can go to 806
806に行くことができます
this is
これは
that's right
それは正しい
this is the sentence
これが文です
I am making an example
例を作っています
our later
私たちの後で
Energy stock
エネルギー在庫
The ancient DNA and some artifacts are given to Beta to make
古代の DNA といくつかのアーティファクトはベータに与えられ、
although it is expensive
高価ですが
One costs more than 10,000 Taiwan dollars
1つ10,000台湾ドル以上します
our next one
私たちの次は
This is what we have to do with this
これが私たちがこれに関してしなければならないことです
XIV and carbon XIV representatives
XIV およびカーボン XIV の代表者
For example, Inao
例えば稲尾さん
The first point is to say the first place
まず第一のポイントは、まず第一に言うことです。
The second place The second place is between 7600 and 7500
2位 2位は7600～7500の間
So much data in the first place
そもそもデータが多すぎる
this is nogu
ノグです
two years old
2歳
Its culture has reached seventy-nine
その文化は79に達しました
almost seven thousand years
ほぼ7000年
Minmin Harbor is from 1638 to 1852 A.D.
ミンミン港は西暦 1638 年から 1852 年まで存在します。
this is the age
これが年齢です
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
Then we will talk about the fifth paragraph of the story.
次に、物語の第 5 段落について説明します。
The fifth story is very important is the study of DNA
5番目の話は非常に重要です、それはDNAの研究です
dna research
DNA研究
we were
私たちはいた
My idea is how we should encourage our own domestic research teams
私の考えは、国内の研究チームをどのように奨励すべきかということです。
I hope to find a partner in China
中国でパートナーを見つけたいと思っています
But then I inquired about the result
しかし、その後結果について尋ねたところ、
The success rate of domestic partners is not high, about one-tenth
国内パートナーの成功率は1/10程度と高くない
Send ten to make one
10個送って1個作る
They doubt everything about his accuracy
彼らは彼の正確さについてすべてを疑っている
I was thinking that we only had this sentence, then there was only number one
この文しかないと思ってたら、1番しかなかった
what to do
何をすべきか
1 out of 10 this can't risk these
10 人中 1 人は危険を冒すことはできません
I will listen more
もっと聞きます
that's very lucky
それはとても幸運です
This is my colleague, Academician Zhang Zhenghua
こちらは私の同僚、学者の張正華です
He happened to be with Germany's Max Plan
彼はたまたまドイツのマックス・プランにいた
With Professor He Yingqing, the vice president of Kaohsiung Medical University at that time
当時高雄医科大学副学長の何英清教授と
he is in contact with him
彼は彼と連絡を取っている
Another day I called him and asked about the domestic DNA
別の日、私は彼に電話して国内の DNA について尋ねました。
Because he said this for a long time, tomorrow, Principal Ge will take his son
ずっと言っていたので、明日、葛校長が息子を連れて行きます
It is his son, President Ge’s son, Mr. Ge Mingxuan, who is a doctoral student at Max Plan in Germany
それは、ドイツのマックス・プランの博士課程の学生である葛総統の息子、葛明軒氏です。
I'm about to graduate now, and I happen to be a doctoral student there.
私はもうすぐ卒業ですが、たまたまそこの博士課程の学生です。
He also made Taiwan's DNA of Taiwan's aborigines
彼はまた、台湾原住民の台湾のDNAを作りました
I think this opportunity is too rare for me, so I hurried to Tainan to meet them
こんな機会は滅多にないので、会いに台南へ急遽向かいました
Once they are of course more interested in the 8000+ years
もちろん、彼らが 8000 年以上に興味を持つようになったら
Because there are more specimens in Nanke, he has 2000 sentences
南柯にはもっと多くの標本があるので、彼の文は2000個あります
But South Kota's earliest is 4800
しかし、サウスコタの最も古いものは4800です
Of course he is most interested in the earliest us of more than 8,000 years
もちろん、彼が最も興味を持っているのは、8,000 年以上前の私たちです。
so take priority
だから優先してください
This Max Plan, this location is world famous
このマックスプラン、この場所は世界的に有名です
Let's see the next one now
さあ、次を見ましょう
I'll talk about us later
私たちのことについては後で話します
Follow Principal Ge, Vice Principal Ge
ゲ校長、ゲ副校長をフォロー
He is now the president and vice president of China Medical University
彼は現在、中国医科大学の学長および副学長を務めています。
This Professor Gu Yinqing, I am with them.
この古銀青教授、私も彼らと一緒です。
His wife accompanied us to Germany
彼の奥さんがドイツに同行してくれました
Send my sample to this institute in person
私のサンプルをこの研究所に直接送ってください
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
This is the Stone King Professor Stone King
これがストーンキングです ストーンキング教授
He is their director
彼は彼らのディレクターです
This and that ethnography this crew
あれこれ民族誌このクルー
This is the vice principal's son
こちらは副校長の息子です
and his team
そして彼のチーム
then i go for the first time
それから初めて行きます
Of course I'm going to do a briefing
もちろん説明会も行います
Do a briefing with them for a photo shoot
写真撮影のためのブリーフィングを行う
But now I want to introduce this Stone King in particular
さて、今回は特にこのストーンキングをご紹介したいと思います
our partners
当社のパートナー
He's just waiting for what I'm going to say
彼はただ私が言うことを待っているだけです
this is who we are now
これが今の私たちです
our current race
私たちの現在の種族
Not at all Homo Sapiens Sapiens
まったくそうではない ホモ・サピエンス・サピエンス
Homo sapiens sapiens
ホモ・サピエンス・サピエンス
His theory is out of Africa
彼の理論はアフリカの外にある
That is, his ancestors changed from Elsang to Africa
つまり、彼の祖先はエルサングからアフリカに変わったのです。
Follow M and N
MとNをフォローしてください
The theory out of Africa
アフリカ発祥の理論
He was published by Professor Stone King and his teacher
この本はストーン・キング教授とその先生によって出版されました。
Now no one doubts his academic
今では彼の学力を疑う人はいない
Because the race is very...
レースはとても大変なので…
This science is that everyone is very...
この科学は、誰もが非常に...
That is to say, between them
つまり、彼らの間では、
It's all very clear
すべては非常に明確です
So he is a very important scholar who came up with African theory
つまり、彼はアフリカ理論を考案した非常に重要な学者です
so we're glad he's working with us
だから彼が私たちと一緒に働いてくれて嬉しいよ
and his son
そして彼の息子
This lady is surnamed Fu
この女性の姓は Fu です
Fu Qiaomei
フー・チャオメイ
Ms. is mainland China
彼女は中国本土です
Graduate students in Beijing
北京の大学院生たち
He is now a graduate
彼はもう卒業しました
If the distance is low, pull it to Harvard University and grab it immediately
距離が短い場合はハーバード大学まで引っ張ってすぐに掴む
snatch him away
彼を奪い去ってください
now at harvard
今はハーバード大学にいる
So he is the master of our DNA extraction
つまり彼は私たちの DNA 抽出の達人なのです
he did it all
彼はすべてをやった
he arrived last christmas
彼は去年のクリスマスに到着しました
he won't go back to beijing
彼は北京には戻らないだろう
He said I dedicated my tribute to your DNA
彼は私があなたの DNA に敬意を表すると言いました
yes do this
はい、これをしてください
ok let's see the next one now
よし、次を見てみよう
At this time, I put this sample
今回はこのサンプルを入れてみました
In the beginning he asked for a leg bone
最初に彼は足の骨を求めました
this straight bone
このまっすぐな骨
this tooth
この歯
Three things to send to the deputy doctor
副医師に送る3つのこと
he accepts our specimens
彼は私たちの標本を受け入れます
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
good
良い
The result of his analysis is
彼の分析の結果は、
this we just saw
これは私たちが見たばかりです
said he was
彼はそう言った
one is 1
1 は 1
Number one is the 10,000 to 10,000 haplogroup
1番は10,000対10,000のハプログループです
Haplogroups, let me explain a bit more
ハプログループについて、もう少し説明しましょう
So haplogroups are Multiconscience
したがって、ハプログループは多良心です
The Hypergroup
ハイパーグループ
It's because of the DNA in our body
それは私たちの体のDNAのせいです
Each DNA trap has 23 pairs of blue bodies
各 DNA トラップには 23 対の青い本体があります。
23 pairs inside
中に23足
22 pairs are all XX
22組はすべてXXです
Only one pair is XY
XY は 1 つのペアのみ
Only the blue sex can have the appearance of Y
Yの外見を持つことができるのは青いセックスだけです
If it is female, it is still XX
女性ならやはり○○です
so in other words
つまり、言い換えれば
Inside each set of DNA
それぞれの DNA セットの内部
23 pairs of blue body inside
中に青い本体が23足入っています。
45/46 is X
45/46はXです
1/46 of only one blue sex is Y
たった 1 つの青い性別の 1/46 が Y です
So 1 is also in other words
つまり 1 は言い換えると
it is more
それはもっとです
So it's easier for him to do
だから彼にとってはやりやすいんだよ
So first make it like this
ということで、まずはこんな感じに作ります
The second sentence is the R9 haplogroup
2 番目の文は R9 ハプログループです
From these two sentences
この二つの文から
He is with R1 and R9
彼はR1とR9と一緒です
They are all related to Taiwanese aboriginal returning soldiers with matrilineal blood relationship
彼らは全員、母系血縁関係を持つ台湾原住民帰還兵と関係がある。
but how much
でもどれくらい
There are very few people in mainland China
中国本土には人がほとんどいない
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
This is the L3 just mentioned
これが先ほど述べた L3 です
When the M comes out
Mが出てきたら
N is mainly
Nは主に
Most of Europe is N
ヨーロッパの大部分はNです
M go from here
ここから行きます
I have always been in mainland China
私はずっと中国本土にいます
Then M looks like this
するとMはこんな感じになります
There are also parts of N that go to the coastline very early
Nの一部では非常に早い段階で海岸線に行くこともあります
all the way to australia
はるばるオーストラリアまで
Then the M branch goes all the way to America
そしてM支店ははるばるアメリカへ
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
Our E is here
私たちのEはここにあります
That is when M came out and Tuhuizhou came out and developed to this generation of M9.
そこに M が登場し、Tuhuizhou が登場し、この世代の M9 に発展しました。
M9 comes out of D probably in this place
DからM9が出てくるのはおそらくここでしょう
So sentence D is this group
つまり、文 D はこのグループです
The second sentence we have to see the next one
2 番目の文は次の文を見なければなりません
The second sentence is N becomes R
2番目の文はNがRになります
R9 is in this place
R9はこんなところにあります
It is this generation that is Tibet, the generation of Izzy Indochina Peninsula
この世代こそがチベット、イジー・インドシナ半島の世代である
I am also a layman
私も素人です
so please advise
それでアドバイスしてください
Thank you, let's look at the next question
ありがとう、次の質問を見てみましょう
This is from L3 from here on M
ここからMのL3からです
We E are this group
私たちEはこのグループです
So R9 is the N group
つまりR9はNグループです
to this group
このグループに
Let's look at the next question
次の質問を見てみましょう
this what i'm going to talk about now
これが今私が話そうとしていることです
this
これ
epilogue
結語
Well, since this Liangdao man was unearthed
さて、この梁島人が発掘されて以来、
we are discussing now
私たちは今議論しています
what problems did he cause
彼はどんな問題を引き起こしたのか
this is my personal opinion
これは私の個人的な意見です
there are nine questions
質問は9つあります
The first is to reinforce the theme of the ocean in ancient China
1 つ目は、古代中国の海のテーマを強化することです。
how do you say that
あなたはそれをどう言う
Just because China includes Taiwan
中国に台湾が含まれているというだけで
At the earliest, all historians focused on the Central Plains
最初はすべての歴史家がセントラルプレーンズに目を向けました
study that place
その場所を勉強してください
The regions on our frontier seem to be understudied
私たちの辺境の地域は十分に研究されていないようです
very few
非常に少ない
This is the difference between a mainstream and some fringe research
これが主流の研究と一部の非主流の研究の違いです
In fact, people from Liangdao more than 8,000 years ago
実際、8,000年以上前に梁島の人々が
he is at sea
彼は海にいる
We can know that
私たちはそれを知ることができます
In fact, it was very early on the edge of the continent in East Asia
実際、それは東アジアの大陸の端で非常に早くから行われていました。
early
早い
Sea nations have been active for a long time
海洋国家は古くから活動してきた
This is what we have been ignoring before
これは私たちがこれまで無視してきたことです
Then this year
それから今年は
From 2030
2030年に
already started now
すでに今始まっています
Many of us have started to notice this
私たちの多くはこのことに気づき始めています
aspects like archeology
考古学のような側面
archeology too
考古学も
Because it used to be dominated by the Central Plains
かつては中原が支配していたので、
Everything Central Plains
セントラル・プレインズのすべて
even our predecessors
私たちの先人たちでさえ
our teachers
私たちの先生方
Mr. Zhang Guangzhi
張光志氏
His research is still in the Central Plains
彼の研究はまだセントラルプレーンズで行われています
For example, his Longshan Luowei
たとえば、彼の龍山羅威
second category
2番目のカテゴリー
It is the school during the trip to Yongsan
龍山旅行中の学校です
He is from Longshan Culture
彼は龍山文化出身です
This coastal generation is all descended from the Longshan travel period.
この沿岸世代は全員、龍山旅行時代の子孫です。
And then until the 1980s
そして1980年代まで
start
始める
In the history of China, there were mainland scholars with strange book handles.
中国の歴史の中に、奇妙な本のハンドルを持つ大陸の学者がいました。
He thinks Chinese history is not like this
彼は中国の歴史はこんなものではないと考えている
He broke the concept
彼は概念を打ち破った
Think that there should be six cultural regions in Chinese history
中国の歴史には6つの文化圏があるべきだと思う
There are six cultural districts in Geju Frontier
済州フロンティアには6つの文化地区がある
In fact, the six cultural districts were all developed at the same time
実は6つの文化地区はすべて同時に発展した
Later, slowly because the Central Plains culture is too strong
中原の文化が強すぎるので後はゆっくり
too powerful
強すぎる
So slowly contact more and more
だからゆっくりどんどん連絡してね
contact them
彼らに連絡してください
you just know something
あなたは何かを知っているだけです
this is mr book handle
これはミスター・ブックハンドルです
Of course, our Mr. Zhang Guangzhi also later
もちろん、私たちの張光志氏も後に
Because this trend also has some changes
この傾向にも変化があるので
so I always just because
だから私はいつもただそれだけの理由で
Later, when I did research on marine guide reputation for me,
その後、マリンガイドの評判について調べてみたところ、
I feel that these ethnic groups should have been earlier
これらの民族はもっと早くに存在すべきだったと思う
It's not because they've been around the coast for a long time
それは彼らが長い間海岸沿いにいたからではありません
float around, walk around, walk around
浮かんで、歩き回って、歩き回って
So the inland culture is completely different from the ocean culture
つまり、内陸の文化と海洋の文化は全く異なるのです。
concept is different
コンセプトが違う
Because the inland cultures are enclosed in one piece
内陸文化は一つの土地に囲まれているため
its resource is the land
その資源は土地です
So everyone has to tell the truth and I will talk more.
だからみんなが真実を語らなければならないし、私はもっと話すつもりだ。
the ocean is not
海はそうではない
The ocean because the sky outside them is too wide
海は外の空が広すぎるから
so they are drifting
だから彼らは漂流している
relatively large liquidity
流動性比較大
This is their characteristic is that they are different from the inland
これが内陸とは違う特徴です。
and their inland culture
そして彼らの内陸文化
Because the resources are there
資源はあるから
they are ac
彼らはACです
Foreign exchanges have long existed
外国為替は古くから存在していた
have been communicating with each other for a long time
長い間お互いにコミュニケーションを取っています
So oceanic culture
つまり海洋文化
And inland culture
そして内陸の文化
It slowly develops into steak
徐々にステーキに成長していきます
nation
国家
Nation into country
国家が国へ
Because it wants to govern the oceanic nation of this land
この地の海洋国家を統治したいから
Not easy to become State
国家になるのは容易ではない
it's not easy
簡単ではない
because it's inherently fluid
本質的に流動的なものだから
I'm not very good at staying in a certain place
私は特定の場所に留まるのがあまり得意ではありません
how will it develop
どのように発展するのでしょうか
looking at the land
土地を見ている
big no
大きないいえ
So Oceanic Networks
ソー・オーシャニック・ネットワークス
like us in taiwan
台湾の私たちのように
why such a big island
なぜこんなに大きな島なのか
is there any country
どこかの国はありますか
no since ancient times
いや、昔から
We arrived at the Han people a little earlier than Zheng Chenggong
鄭成功よりも少し早く漢民族に到着しました。
It is now more than four hundred years ago
今から四百年以上前のことになります
when come
いつ来ますか
Taiwan is still mostly aborigines
台湾は今でも原住民がほとんど
many tribes
多くの部族
come here to live together
一緒に暮らすためにここに来てください
it lives here
それはここに住んでいます
It is not easy to become State
国家になるのは簡単ではない
This is where the ocean is different
ここが海と違うところです
So I think it's time to be afraid
だから恐れる時が来たと思う
ocean population
海洋人口
Research on this aspect must be strengthened
この側面に関する研究を強化する必要がある
the second
二番目
Of course, because we studied
もちろん勉強したからには
The prehistoric cultural sequence along the Mijiang coast
密江海岸沿いの先史時代の文化の流れ
Their earliest was Ke Qiutou
彼らの最古の人物は柯秋頭である
Fujian Pingtang
福建平塘
Ke Qiu voted that his age would not exceed seven thousand years
柯秋は自分の年齢が7000歳を超えないことに投票した
Now if we assume Liangdao people
さて、梁島人を仮定すると、
This is eight thousand and seven thousand words
これは8700語です
to break their sequence
彼らの順序を壊すために
I'm afraid to be in their
彼らの中にいるのが怖い
This Liangdao culture was earlier than them
この梁島の文化は彼らよりも早かった
this is the third
これは3番目です
Chronology of divergence of the origin of the Austronesian universe
オーストロネシア宇宙の起源の分岐年表
because
なぜなら
The main committee may understand
主要委員会は理解するかもしれない
so-called universe
いわゆる宇宙
because the universe's two
宇宙は二つだから
how is the universe
宇宙はどうですか
I tell you something in common
共通点をお話します
i can communicate
私はコミュニケーションをとることができます
such a group
そのようなグループ
But it doesn't mean
でもそれは意味がない
Bloodborne is the bloodline of the unified race
Bloodborne は統一種族の血統
at this point
この時点で、
so we can see
それで私たちは見ることができます
You can tell from the two sentences of Liangdao
梁島の二文を見ればわかる
One sentence is one one
一つの文は一つです
One sentence is twenty nine
1文は29です
where did twenty nine come from
二十九はどこから来たのですか
what i just said
私が今言ったこと
it is from indochina peninsula from burma
インドシナ半島からビルマ産です
Inner Belt of Tibet and Burma
チベットとビルマの内側ベルト
Exhibition to Indochina Peninsula
インドシナ半島への展示
Just arrived in the southern ocean area
南方海域に到着しました
One is from the M9 in Mainland China
1 つは中国本土の M9 からのもの
It turned out to be in this area
このエリアにあることが判明
So to express two sentences we found
したがって、2 つの文を表現するには、次のことがわかりました。
already two different groups
すでに2つの異なるグループ
You can see that the sea peoples in our ancient area
私たちの古代地域に海の民がいたことがわかります。
How divided is his ethnic group
彼の民族グループはどの程度分裂しているのか
How many different ethnic groups does he have
彼には何種類の民族グループがいますか
So this is his age division
これが彼の年齢区分です
wide open
大きく開く
Because the South Island has
南の島にはあるので、
Now, for example, the academician Lirengui of our academy
さて、たとえば、私たちのアカデミーの学者リレンギは、
They kept pushing and pushing until maybe six thousand years
彼らはおそらく6000年まで押し続けました
I saw it the other day
先日見ました
Did Lan Daoyu dare not say six thousand years ago?
蘭道宇はあえて6000年前とは言わなかったのだろうか？
he thinks not
彼はそうは思わない
Recently, I was at Connel University with Mr. Mei Zhulin
最近、私はメイ・ズーリンさんとコネル大学にいました。
He recently corresponded with him
彼は最近彼と文通しました
on these issues
これらの問題について
that is
あれは
should they linguists because they think
彼らはこう考えているので、言語学者はそうすべきなのでしょうか？
Blue Sword Feather is
青い剣の羽は
It is generally believed to be branched from Bluetooth
一般的にはBluetoothから分岐したものと考えられています
but
しかし
When their blue sword feather appeared
蒼き剣の羽根が現れた時
is already a full-fledged language
すでに本格的な言語です
So they all think that there should be a language
だから彼らは皆、言語があるべきだと考えている
It is gradually used from Bluetooth to Blue Daoyu
BluetoothからBlue Daoyuまで徐々に使用中
have a status
ステータスがある
maybe this is
たぶんこれは
linguists to study
勉強する言語学者
not us archaeologists
私たち考古学者ではありません
so-called research questions
いわゆるリサーチクエスチョン
This is
これは
So the linguist actually asks
言語学者の実際の質問は
differentiation problem
微分問題
Probably know
おそらく知っています
Because when Taiwan split up
台湾が分裂したときだから
It's only about 4,000 to 5,000 years old
たった4,000～5,000年前のものです
Li Dover
リー・ドーバー
not more than six thousand years
6000年以内
So this age of differentiation is like this
この差別化の時代はこんな感じ
So
それで
South Island and Bamboo
南の島と竹
actually when
実際にいつ
this
これ
This is their linguist
これは彼らの言語学者です
probably place to try again later
おそらく後でもう一度試してみる場所
That
それか
generally believed
一般に信じられている
East Asia is the birthplace of Austronesian languages
東アジアはオーストロネシア語の発祥の地です
that this
これは
because former linguists
元言語学者だから
always
いつも
There are two important schools of thought
重要な考え方には 2 つの学派があります
one is considered to be
1つは次のように考えられます
Austronesian should
オーストロネシア人はこうすべきだ
It should be China from Tibet to Sichuan to the Yangtze River Basin and then down
チベットから四川省、長江流域、そして下流までは中国のはずだ
Go down from the mouth of the Yangtze River Basin and go southeast
長江流域の河口から南東に下りる
A group of American scholars said that
アメリカの学者グループはこう言った。
He thinks his language should be a trade language
彼は自分の言語が貿易言語であるべきだと考えている
is a language of trade
貿易言語です
Because everyone is talking about this
みんながこのことについて話しているから
These two academic
この二人の学者は
But if everyone has overturned the victim's academic theory by now
でももし今頃誰もが被害者の学説を覆しているとしたら
Probably everyone believes that Taiwan is the mother emperor
おそらく誰もが台湾が母なる皇帝であると信じている
Because Taiwan is the most complicated place for Nan Daoyu
ナン・ダオユにとって台湾は最も複雑な場所だから
Often the place where a language appears most complex
多くの場合、言語が最も複雑に見える場所
it was one of the earliest locations
それは最も初期の場所の一つでした
If Taiwan
台湾なら
but so early
でもとても早い
So it's at the place of origin
つまり原点にあるのです
where
どこ
won't be taiwan
台湾ではないでしょう
because all Taiwanese
全員台湾人だから
Aboriginal people now
今のアボリジニの人たち
It's all coming in from the outside
すべては外から入ってくるものです
mostly chinese
ほとんど中国人
Southeast coast
南東海岸
The Indochina Peninsula in the South China Sea brings
南シナ海のインドシナ半島は、
So this place of origin
ということで、この出身地は
can be sure
確かにできる
already knocked over this
もうこれを倒しました
The scholarship on the origin of the island domains of Southeast Asia
東南アジアの島嶼の起源に関する研究
This is
これは
So what about the domestic route?
では国内線はどうなるのでしょうか？
this
これ
probably with
おそらく一緒に
now for now
今は今のところ
Both agree that it is from Taiwan
両者とも台湾産であることに同意する
into the Philippines
フィリピンへ
To this South China Sea, this Indonesia
この南シナ海へ、このインドネシアへ
Island baby
アイランドベイビー
been going east
東に進み続ける
still going west
まだ西へ行く
all the way to masgas
マスガスまでずっと
this area
この地域
then this
それからこれ
The country's route
国の路線
because
なぜなら
if still
まだなら
Originally from mainland China
中国本土出身
They are all from China
彼らは全員中国出身です
It also needs to be rethought on the way of its diffusion
普及のあり方も考え直す必要がある
So that's what I think the problem with the ocean's late-night habits
それが海の深夜の習慣の問題だと私は思います
Many people have been thinking about saying
こう言うことを考えている人も多いでしょう
Do you think the universe will expand?
宇宙は膨張すると思いますか?
Because of the influence of the emergence of rice culture
稲作文化の出現の影響で
Then if Liangdao eight thousand years ago
8000年前に梁島だったら
this we saw it
これを私たちは見ました
Apparently Bright Island is not a place that will be able to grow
どうやらブライトアイランドは成長できる場所ではないらしい
What is the plowing place for planting
植栽のための耕起場所はどこですか
So it might be looking for the universe
だからそれは宇宙を探しているのかもしれない
Its late night is mainly hunting and gathering at sea
深夜は主に海で狩猟採集が行われます
while the rice is in
ご飯が入っている間に
I'm afraid it's a relatively late flower show.
比較的遅めのお花見だと思います。
So its fluid habit
その流動的な習慣
Might also be a question to think about
考えるべき質問でもあるかもしれません
The eighth is the archaeological field method
8つ目は考古学フィールド法です
This technical update when the human bone was excavated
人骨発掘時の技術アップデート
I said that I am afraid that we will meet in the future
私は将来会うことになるのが怖いと言いました
Human bones must wear yellow clothes
人間の骨は黄色い服を着なければなりません
I think that's probably an important point
たぶんそれが重要なポイントだと思う
The fourth is
4つ目は
Previously because of this DNA study on the island of Goran
以前はゴラン島でのこの DNA 研究が原因でした
has been less successful
あまり成功していない
what's the main thing
主なものは何ですか
Because DNA extraction is too difficult
DNA抽出が難しすぎるため
Let me know when we talk about Stone King
ストーンキングについて話すときは教えてください
he told the truth
彼は真実を言いました
The extraction success rate of DNA from a thousand years ago is extremely low
千年前のDNA抽出成功率は極めて低い
Not to mention our eight thousand years of success
私たちの8000年にわたる成功は言うまでもありません
It has been successful for more than seven thousand years
7000年以上成功してきた
but then again
でもまたまた
Stone King they became famous because
ストーン・キング 彼らが有名になったのは、
Ye'an successfully obtained the DNA sequence of 40,000 years ago
イェアン氏は4万年前のDNA水配列の取得に成功した
So its technology is always improving
そのため、その技術は常に向上しています
So this is also possible in the future
なので、将来的にはこれも可能です
The research of our Liangdao people may stimulate these questions
梁島の人々の研究はこれらの疑問を刺激するかもしれません
let's see the next one
次を見ましょう
alright
大丈夫
This is roughly what I figured out. Let’s talk about some not very important ones.
これが私が大まかに考え出したことですが、あまり重要ではないいくつかのことについて話しましょう。
I also have a few books currently
私も今何冊か本を持っています
I thought everyone would take turns
みんな順番にやると思ってた
Welcome to these three books
この 3 冊の本へようこそ
My report looks like this for the first time
私のレポートは初めてこんな感じになりました
The second discovery of Liangdao people's DNA research another book
梁島人のDNA研究の第二の発見 別の本
In addition to this we have already discussed in some papers
これに加えて、いくつかの論文ですでに議論しました
some papers
いくつかの論文
Also in the international
インターナショナルでも
It was in March last year
去年の3月でした
I already have one
すでに持っています
I followed a family
家族を追っていきました
Together we all wrote
みんなで一緒に書きました
This was published in the American Journal of Human Genetics in the United States
これは米国のAmerican Journal of Human Geneticsに掲載されました。
This is the world's top magazine published
これは世界で発行されているトップ雑誌です
So our job is roughly
つまり、私たちの仕事は大まかに言うと、
I have this next
次はこれを持っています
we have an article coming out soon
近々公開予定の記事があります
In the following university I published a paper
以下の大学で論文を発表しました
I published this one in this
こちらの記事で公開しました
This is in the EPA
これはEPAに載っています
It was published by the Indo-Pacific Institute of Pedagogical Studies
インド太平洋教育研究所によって出版されました。
This paper is probably
この紙はおそらく
We're all in the process and we're all still publishing
私たちは全員がそのプロセスの途中であり、まだ公開中です
ok let's see the next one
はい、次を見ましょう
Our current research work
私たちが現在行っている研究活動
Research on the Periphery of Culture
文化周縁研究
we must
我々はしなければならない
because it's so bright
とても明るいので
Cultures found in this location
この場所で見られる文化
According to his unearthed naughty, stony
彼の発掘されたいたずらな石によると
especially spine
特に背骨
The county magistrate's favorite fisherman
縣長所最熱愛的漁差
What the hell is it around
一体その辺は何なんだろう
What is the relationship with the surrounding culture?
周囲の文化とどのような関係があるのでしょうか？
this is what we are going to study
これが私たちが勉強することです
This behavior avoids learning
この行動は学習を妨げます
this is to be studied
これは勉強するべきだ
paleoenvironmental science is very important
古環境科学は非常に重要です
paleoenvironmental studies when I was working in Liangdao
梁島で働いていた時の古環境研究
i just noticed
さっき気付いた
I wonder why such a small island
なんでこんな小さな島なんだろう
How could it be so popular after 8,000 years
8,000年経ってもどうしてこれほど人気が​​あるのでしょうか？
I pay attention to this ecological environment
この生態環境に注目しています
because the horse owner
なぜなら馬主は
This Daegu guy said
大邱のこの男は言いました
must go there every year
毎年そこに行かなければなりません
so he can see umbrella terroir
そうすれば彼は傘のテロワールを見ることができる
And this ecological environment
そしてこの生態環境は
8,000 years ago, the sea level
8,000年前の海面
with this now
今はこれで
what is the change
変化は何ですか
I once asked academician Liu Shaocheng of our research institute
私はかつて私たちの研究所の学者、劉少成に尋ねました。
He said that eight thousand years is about 10 meters lower
八千年は約10メートル低いと彼は言いました
Well, Professor Chen Wanshan from the Geology Department of National Taiwan University
さて、国立台湾大学地質学部の陳万山教授
Say about 10 meters to 20 meters
10メートルから20メートルくらいでしょうか
Academician Liu recently told me
学者のリュー氏が最近私にこう言いました。
He said that there is no 10 meters or about 3 or 4 meters.
１０メートルもない、３、４メートルくらいだという。
So the doctrine keeps changing
つまり教義は変わり続ける
All in all he is lowered
全体として彼はレベルが下がっている
I'm watching while lowering
下げながら見てます
because i'm on a cliff
私は崖の上にいるので
The mainland fishermen are fishing there
本土の漁師たちがそこで漁をし​​ている
he's in the shallow water
彼は浅瀬にいる
I'm thinking if it's lower than 10 meters
10メートル以下なら考えてます
Presumably his part is because the fishing ground is so
おそらく彼の役割は、漁場が非常に優れているためです
Every day when we dig there
毎日そこを掘ると
he harvests below
彼は下で収穫します
how is he
彼はどのように
Come here every morning and don't go down
毎朝ここに来て、降りないでください
this ichthyosaur
この魚竜
send down the fish bowl
金魚鉢を下に送ります
Help Maru collect the ichthyosaur and go back
マルが魚竜を集めて戻るのを手伝ってください
Lay another ichthyosaur down
別の魚竜を寝かせる
Twice a day pays off
1日2回でも効果あり
so
それで
How about it
どうでしょうか
when it's bone
骨のとき
If the sea level shift decreases
海面変動が減少すると
its soup map
そのスープマップ
Bigger face
大きな顔
Tang Tu maybe that place Tang Lou Kuan
Tang Tu たぶんあの場所 Tang Lou Kuan
So its fish production is booming
そのため、魚の生産が盛んになっています
More magnification
倍率多
So this is also our bone environment
つまり、これは私たちの骨の環境でもあります
research is later
研究は後ほど
solving issues
問題を解決する
and the bone environment for
そして骨の環境は
Oxygen isotope analysis, etc.
酸素同位体分析など
Animals, plants, grilled bones, etc.
動物、植物、焼き骨など。
certainly
当然
Our work
私たちの仕事
after making it
作った後
So my most important thing is
だから私が最も重要なことは
i cook bone roast in taiwan
台湾で骨付きローストを作ります
Be sure to talk to the local people
ぜひ地元の人に話しかけてみてください
I think
私が思うに
Artifacts from this place
この場所から出土した工芸品
should stay here
ここに留まるべきです
so
それで
We measure the whole
全体を計測します
For all the work of Matsu, I exchanged the specimens in the Matsu Folk Museum
馬祖の作品については、馬祖民俗資料館の標本を交換しました。
because it's local
地元だから
How can it have this social collection is what they want to collect
彼らが収集したいものをこのソーシャルコレクションにするにはどうすればよいですか
Social education is focused on their native land
社会教育は故郷に焦点を当てています
This is my always Le Wei's policy
これが私のいつものLe Weiのポリシーです
how do you see the next one
次はどうなりますか？
Future goals Of course I want to deepen this research work
今後の目標 もちろん研究を深めていきたい
Algorithms of Institutional Capability
制度的能力のアルゴリズム
Issues related to the stock environment
株式環境に関する課題
practical strategy
実践的な戦略
Research on the Peripheral Correlation of Material Culture
物質文化の周縁相関に関する研究
In this way, lead to a comparative study on No. 1 and No. 2
こうしてNo.1とNo.2の比較検討につながる
this has to be done
これはやらなければいけない
This is what we have done now
これが私たちが今やったことです
I recently went to inspect the opening at this site
先日この現場の開口部を視察しに行ってきました
History Museum at History I Nanhai Road
南海歴史一路にある歴史博物館
is still on exhibition
まだ展示中です
as free to see
自由に見れるので
This guide and the archeology led by Mazu
このガイドと媽祖が導く考古学
Then we still have our model anyway
とにかくモデルがまだ残っています
we all made it
私たちは皆それをやり遂げました
what we model
私たちがモデル化するもの
The model of the face is being done now
顔のモデルは現在作成中です
not done yet
まだやっていない
And we except human bones
そして私たちは人骨を除いて
What do we want the guard's face to look like?
警備員の顔をどのように見せたいですか?
So this is hope for our future work
これは私たちの将来の仕事への希望です
I'll take another look
もう一度見てみましょう
This is the long picture I sent just now
これは私が送ったばかりの長い写真です
This word this is my mediocrity
この言葉 これが私の凡庸さ
this is not good
これは良くない
this is not a good poem
これは良い詩ではありません
I wrote the sequence like this
シーケンスはこんな感じで書きました
Just give it to the present boss
今の上司に渡してください
This Shuhua family is my senior brother
この朱華家は私の兄です
I have learned from Huang Beiyue's Shuhua family before
私は以前、黄北岳の朱華家から学んだことがあります。
So I haven't written for decades
だから何十年も書いてなかった
I can't write my words
自分の言葉が書けない
dare not measure
あえて測らない
So I asked my brother to write this name
だから先輩にこの名前を書いてもらいましょう
give to present
プレゼントする
thank you
ありがとう
professor thank you
ありがとう教授
wonderful speech
素晴らしいスピーチ
first question
最初の質問
i want to ask
聞きたいです
that professor is
あの教授は
professor
教授
you think you like
あなたはそれが好きだと思いますか
Your favorite
あなたのお気に入り
the professor is
教授は
that about this
それについて
This number two massive girl
このナンバー2の巨大な女の子
and sister
和妹母孩
just say
言うだけ
his Yanwu
彼のヤンウー
was taken away
連れ去られた
Then I want to know the story too
私もその話が知りたいです
just take this
これだけ取ってください
what is the motive for taking
取る動機は何ですか
then bring that
それからそれを持ってきてください
It was our Yangxian leader who found it.
それを見つけたのは私たちの陽県リーダーでした。
Elder brother He Qin, our Yang line is long
何秦兄よ、私たちのヤンラインは長いです
tell us the secret
秘密を教えてください
how is it
どうですか
How did you get him back?
どうやって彼を取り戻しましたか？
get it back as a whole
全体的に元に戻してください
how difficult is it
どれくらい難しいですか
The second is to say
2つ目は、こう言うことです
all of us
私たち全員
that bug bone
あの虫の骨
worm bone of the whole wrist
手首全体の虫骨
The teeth you see are so neat
見える歯はとてもきれいです
that is to say this
つまりこれは言う
ancient man's teeth
古代人の歯
Is it all like this? Is it so good?
全部こんな感じでいいの？
Is it because they belong to the exaltation of the ocean?
それは彼らが海の高揚に属しているからでしょうか？
So capture more here
ここでさらにキャプチャします
How can there be such a complete one?
どうしてこのような完全なものが存在するのでしょうか？
thank you thank you
ありがとうありがとう
Thank you Madam, what is your last name?
ありがとうございます、奥様、あなたの苗字は何ですか？
Shuang Mulin
双木林
Miss Ray
ミス・レイ
I'm going to apply for this now
今からこれに応募してみます
Because of the above three problems
上記3つの問題があるため、
I give everyone a souvenir of mine
みんなに私の記念品をあげます
This souvenir is an 8G USB
このお土産は8G USBです
and it has my name written
そしてそこには私の名前が書かれています
light up commemorative
ライトアップ記念
this souvenir
このお土産
thank you professor
ありがとう教授
I will answer first
まず答えます
answer the question first
先回答問題
Let the magistrate answer his questions again
判事にもう一度質問に答えてもらいましょう
The first question is
最初の質問は
why can't i go into details
なぜ詳細に触れられないのですか
It's because it's more tortuous in the middle
真ん中が曲がりくねっているからです
and involved in the scene
そして現場に関わっている
The military is still scouting for undisclosed festivals
軍はまだ未公開のフェスティバルを偵察中
so i can't tell anyone
だから誰にも言えない
probably a light
おそらく光
one light
一つの光
Only then did he realize the importance of this tooth
そのとき初めて彼はこの歯の重要性に気づきました
Because in our conception before
なぜなら、以前の私たちの概念では
I always thought that teeth are the best place to store DNA
私はいつも歯がDNAを保存するのに最適な場所だと思っていました
The study of teeth is the most important
歯の研究が最も重要です
But in fact I just said
でも実はさっき言ったんです
Sent three specimens to Germany
3つの標本をドイツに送った
teeth failed
歯が失敗した
Such a long leg bone did not succeed
このような長い脚の骨は成功しませんでした
Great work by the little ice cubes
小さな氷が素晴らしい仕事をしてくれました
It is the front of the big touch paper
ビッグタッチペーパーの表面です
Small straight bone succeeded
小さなまっすぐな骨が成功しました
Most continued to succeed
ほとんどが成功し続けた
OK
OK
this is the first question
これが最初の質問です
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
I'm probably the problem
おそらく私が問題なのです
right
右
I answer
私が答える
That County Magistrate Yang, do you want to tell us about yourself?
ヤン県判事、あなた自身について話したいですか？
how did you find out
あなたはどのようにして知りました
Thank you, teacher
ありがとう、先生
press press talk
プレス プレストーク
no more no more
もうだめ、もうだめ
over there this
あそこにこれ
Well
良い
Let's talk about the embarrassing incident first
まずは恥ずかしい出来事から話しましょう
then
それから
uh we judge
ああ、私たちが判断する
judge say
判決は言う
uh, someone who does this kind of thing
ああ、こういうことをする人
Not many people do this kind of thing
こういうことをする人はあまりいない
uh everyone knows
ああ、みんな知ってるよ
if at home
それが家なら
dropped things
落としたもの
hand stolen words
手で盗んだ言葉
There is a chance to defend the direction
方向性を守るチャンスはある
he is a direct hit
彼は直撃者だ
If I get poached, I'll talk and laugh
もし密猟されたら、話して笑うよ
He was poached at a very young age, expressing that he is familiar with this environment
彼は幼い頃に密猟され、この環境には慣れていると語った
probably answer like this later
おそらく後でこのように答えます
This was found in a safe in Taichung
台中の金庫から発見されました
because
なぜなら
I
私
I like being a detective better than being a doctor
私は医者であるよりも探偵である方が好きです
Ha ha ha ha
ハハハッハッハ
in addition
加えて
Well
良い
We just said the head of the membership
先ほど会員の責任者と言いましたが、
For core core difference
コアコア違いについて
very interested why very interested because
とても興味がある なぜとても興味があるのか
Teacher Chen dug the broken part for the first time
チェン先生は壊れた部分を初めて掘りました
later on
後で
I've figured out what he's all about
彼が何について話しているのか理解できた
The result was in when digging in the second round
2周目で掘ったときに結果が出ました
dig out the whole
全体を掘り出す
Well
良い
I have a
私は持っています
The friend who wrote the fishing exhibition in Taiwan is called Li Jialiang
台湾での釣りの展示会を書いた友人は李佳良といいます
Fishing known as Taiwan
台湾という名の釣り
The world has written many articles
世界はたくさんの記事を書いています
he told me
彼は私に言った
more than ten thousand years ago
一万年以上前
There are people in Taiwan who are willing to make up for the surplus
台湾には余剰分を補おうとする人々がいる
so this
したがって、この
suddenly we see
突然私たちは見る
when the gap was broken
ギャップが壊れたとき
imagine what it should be like
それがどうあるべきかを想像してください
When we look at that full residual
その完全な残差を見ると
Let's see him every step of the way
あらゆる段階で彼を見てみましょう
every place
どこでも
his function
彼の役割
What is his anatomical function
彼の解剖学的機能は何ですか
he has his function
彼には彼の役割がある
when i saw
私が見たとき
Is it Yucha or the original Yugou?
ユウチャですか、それともオリジナルのユウゴですか？
later thought
後で考えた
he should be Yuchai
彼はユチャイであるべきだ
because the front is pointed
前が尖っているので
For the convenience of founding
創立の便宜のため
he has hook
彼はフックを持っています
is to prevent drag peach
ドラッグピーチを防ぐためです
In addition
加えて
There is a hook for the rope
ロープ用のフックがあります
specially engraved
特別に刻印された
means to say
言う意味
At that time there must be a rope to hold
その時は掴むロープがあるはずだ
But now after the fish cavity is played
しかし今、魚の空洞が演奏された後
let it run over the line pull
ラインプルの上を走らせます
Ears running from Bright Island One at the same time
ブライトアイランドワンから同時に流れる耳
Has the inherent disease of divers
ダイバー特有の病気を持っている
We boldly recommend that people from Liangdao are second only to diving.
梁島の人にはダイビングに次ぐことを大胆にお勧めします。
But the main interest is those things
しかし、主な関心はそれらのことです
The environment in which we recruit
私たちが採用する環境
In the environment where we grew up, I feel that these are very familiar
私たちが育った環境では、とても身近に感じます
We just took what we found
私たちは見つけたものをただ受け取っただけです
Imagine and fight with the classmates at that time
あの時のクラスメイトたちを想像して戦ってみよう
found that archeology and anthropology are both interesting
考古学と人類学はどちらも興味深いと感じた
thank you all
皆さん、ありがとうございました
I just changed my answer to your question.
あなたの質問に対する答えを変更しました。
about teeth
歯について
This tooth is 32 grams of teeth all in
この歯は全部で 32 グラムの歯です
probably
おそらく
this is our luck
これは私たちの幸運です
so unnecessary
とても不必要です
who else
他に誰
second place
二位
OK, let's take a look first.
わかりました、見てみましょう
let me ask this
これを聞いてみましょう
1600's economy team
1600年代のエコノミーチーム
Looks like it grew from a heterosexual body
異性愛者の体から生えたように見える
right
右
not from that
それからではない
The human body is grown from high school
人間の体は高校生から成長する
These two are different ones
この二つは別物です
series people
シリーズの人
heterogeneous
異質な
The nucleus is not from the nucleus
核は核から来たものではない
from the cytoplasm
細胞質から
While looking for this
これを探しているうちに
it should have several pairs
いくつかのペアがあるはずです
what we call factor
私たちがファクターと呼ぶもの
So it should if found
したがって、見つかった場合はそうする必要があります
The economic team in 1900 was quite long
1900 年の経済チームは非常に長かった
According to this should also find
これによると、次も見つかります
BMA of other parts
その他の部品のBMA
If there is more BMA
BMAが多い場合
Will this detection classification
この検出分類は
be more precise
もっと正確に
The other is to say
もう一つは、こう言うことです
this number 2
この数字2
It's hundreds of years late
何百年も遅れてるよ
But now it's a different job
でも今は違う仕事だよ
Could it be that they prove each other
もしかしたら彼らはお互いを証明し合っているのかもしれない
Sometimes the early days come and conquer this early stage
時々、初期の日が来て、この初期段階を克服します
Or what, so if you cancel the tail, I will just cancel you
それとも、尾をキャンセルするなら、私はあなたをキャンセルします
That is the key to whether you will have the possibility this time
それが今回の可能性があるかどうかの鍵です
That
それか
The first question I want to answer is about
私が答えたい最初の質問は、
right
右
In fact, the so-called DNA
実は、いわゆるDNAは、
That is its whole and complete yin and shoulder skin.
それはその全体の完全な陰と肩の皮膚です。
There is a muscle reducing pair
筋肉を減らすペアがあります
So the main thing is that it needs a lot of stink, that is, it stinks.
したがって、重要なことは、大量の悪臭が必要である、つまり臭いということです。
A card to it don't let it have missing
カードを紛失しないようにしてください
So what I just said is
それで、私が今言ったことは、
what i just said is
私が今言ったことは
because it was made because its experimental results become
実験結果がこうなるために作られたものだから
There are 16569 clip pairs that can be very complete
非常に完全なクリップ ペアが 16569 個あります
so it can make its sequence out when
そのため、次の場合にシーケンスを実行できるようになります。
1 Between 10,000 and 10,000 A
1 10,000 ～ 10,000 A
it's me because i didn't do it myself
自分でやったわけではないのでそれは私です
I don't know very well
よくわかりません
But I understand it this Metrocontrast is what it is
しかし、私はそれがこのメトロコントラストであることを理解しています
But about Why Cramor Song
でも、Why Cramor Songについては
Now in fact we haven't published
今、実際には公開していません
In fact, the one made is between O1 and O1A
実際に作られたのはO1とO1Aの間です
Why can't this be published now?
なぜこれを今公開できないのでしょうか？
Because they do this DNA research business
彼らはこの DNA 研究事業を行っているため、
It cannot be published arbitrarily
勝手に公開することはできません
announced one day
ある日発表された
its thesis
その論文
it's going to be discounted
それは割引されるだろう
People think you've published
人々はあなたが出版したと思っています
so it's like this
だからそれはこんな感じ
So I'm just getting started
だから私はまだ始めたばかりです
Certain papers are currently being written
特定の論文は現在執筆中です
to be lighter
軽くなる
The second question is
2番目の質問は、
These two sentences are because you want
この 2 つの文は、あなたが望んでいるからです
What I just said was
私が今言ったのは、
ocean of this generation
この世代の海
It's basically multi-ethnic groups wandering and drifting
それは基本的に多民族のグループが放浪し漂流していることです
so today i come tomorrow
だから今日は明日来ます
Longing for them to be hundreds of years apart
彼らが何百年も離れていることを切望しています
so what is their relationship in the middle
それで、真ん中の彼らの関係は何ですか？
we really don't know
私たちは本当に知りません
But the odds are too high
しかし確率が高すぎる
because think about it
考えてみてください
In ancient times, if these ethnic groups drifted on the sea
太古の昔、これらの民族が海に漂着していたら
Because why can we differentiate
なぜ差別化できるのかというと、
different ethnic groups
さまざまな民族グループ
Mainly because we can have mutation
主に突然変異が起こる可能性があるからです
there will be this change
この変化があるでしょう
mutation
突然変異
The result of the mutation will be
突然変異の結果は次のようになります
Almost said a mutation before
以前は突然変異と言われそうになった
It takes about 8,000 years for the human master to mutate
人間の主人が突然変異するのに約8000年かかる
So I believe that those who study them think that there may be a picture in about 5000-3000 years
したがって、それらを研究している人は、約5000年から3000年後に絵があるかもしれないと考えていると思います
There may be a group of pictures
集合写真もあるかもしれない
So we don't know yet
だからまだ分からない
Apparently it's because it's two different matrilines
どうやらそれは2つの異なる母系であるためです
And we know that its fine drop is from the generation from the war to the Indochina Peninsula
そして、その細かい滴は、戦争からインドシナ半島にかけての世代のものであることがわかります。
One is our southeast coast of China
一つは中国の南東海岸です
So its origin is these two different origins
つまり、その起源はこれら 2 つの異なる起源です
Apparently it's done differently
どうやら作り方が違うようです
But I forgot to mention that Germans are beautiful
でも言い忘れましたが、ドイツ人は美しいです
Very grown up our yellow clothes
とても大人になった私たちの黄色い服
He said it was a pioneering work
先駆的な作品だと彼は言った
He said the DNA I made turned out to be zero pollution
彼は、私が作った DNA は汚染がゼロであることが判明したと言いました
no pollution at all
全く汚染がありません
so it's very clear
それはとても明らかです
Every part of the stories I just told is important.
私が今話した物語のどの部分も重要です。
every link is important
どのリンクも重要です
If a link is missing, I am afraid
リンクが切れていたらごめんなさい
Of course we are responsible for this.
もちろん、これについては私たちに責任があります。
This is what I want to answer
これが私が答えたいことです
I want to give this friend
この友達にあげたい
once or twice
一二回
I would like to ask the professor
教授にお聞きしたいのですが
What I just said is more related to the results of the exam
私が今言ったことは試験の結果にもっと関係があります
I was wondering if you could tell us more about
もっと詳しく教えていただけないかと思ったのですが、
About people around the island
島の周りの人々について
They were born anthropologically
彼らは人類学的に生まれました
what kind of state is it
どのような状態ですか
Especially at the place where the white tent was just now
特にさっきまで白いテントがあった場所は
all in water
全部水の中
In that state, many ancient people were academic officials
その州では、多くの古代人が学術関係者でした
seniors accounted for high
シニア層の割合が高い
Then life learns the zone of life
そのとき、人生は人生のゾーンを学びます
Because the islander has less than one
島民が出会ったのは1人未満だったため
so how could they be in the same voice
ではどうして彼らは同じ声でいられるのでしょうか
and some headlines
そしていくつかの見出し
how should their lives be
彼らの人生はどうあるべきか
To be introduced from the University section
大学編から紹介します
Thanks
ありがとう
Actually the story is too long
実はこの話は長すぎるんです
I'm afraid I'm going to make a long story short
長い話を短くしてしまうのが残念ですが
This is our archeology guy
これは私たちの考古学者です
Because especially prehistoric archeology
なぜなら、特に先史時代の考古学は、
Because he has no written record
書面による記録がないため
so all these jobs
つまり、これらすべての仕事は
material culture
物質文化
come tell us some stories
話を聞かせに来てください
we're going to create it
私たちがそれを作成します
These are prehistoric artifacts
これらは先史時代の遺物です
We are left with these words
私たちはこの言葉を残しています
The second is his ecological environment
2つ目は彼の生態環境です
leave it to us
私たちにお任せください
this question is important
この質問は重要です
My guess on this ecological environment
この生態環境についての私の推測
Our place just now
たった今の僕らの場所
It turns out that there is nothing wrong with him being a cliff. It should be an evil soul, but this cross section is only possible because the road opened.
崖であることは何の問題もないことが判明し、邪悪な魂であるはずですが、この断面は道が開いたからこそ可能です。
So it turned out that when they came down from the northeast, the place of the evil soul could probably block some wind. This is why they should only live in the inner zone at the earliest.
そのため、北東から降りてきた場合、悪霊の住む場所は風を遮る可能性があることが判明し、早めに内側のゾーンにのみ住む必要があることがわかりました。
But their place of residence, and we found that the second place is a little bit past that place, and that place is flatter, maybe that place is where they live and throw garbage here,
しかし、彼らの居住地、そして2番目の場所は、その場所を少し過ぎたところにあることがわかりました。そこはもっと平らで、おそらくその場所は彼らが住んでいて、ここにゴミを捨てている場所であり、
It can also be pushed to the cold field with great difficulty, maybe it is like this, but then again, the phenomenon of the fire pit under the second sentence is obviously a place where people live, and people live there and live here.
大変な苦労をして寒い野原に押し込むこともできます、多分こんな感じだと思いますが、やはり、二番目の文の下の火の穴の現象は、明らかに人が住んでいる場所であり、そこに人が住んでいて、ここに住んでいます。
So we're still working on that.
それで、私たちはまだそれに取り組んでいます。
Of course, the relationship is also very close, a great relationship. The inner land is obviously not very easy to live in, so I am talking about, in our prison ecology, a very important point for people living in prisons is that the big island is often attached to the mainland, and the small island is attached to the big island.
もちろん、関係性も非常に親密で、素晴らしい関係です。内地は明らかに住みやすいものではありません。そこで私が話しているのは、刑務所の生態系において、刑務所で暮らす人々にとって非常に重要な点は、大きな島は本土に隣接していることが多く、小さな島は本土に隣接しているということです。大きな島へ。
An island domain is a complete ecological environment, but the material conditions inside are limited. Many things have to be exchanged with each other.
島の領域は完全な生態環境ですが、内部の物質的条件は限られています。多くのものを相互に交換する必要があります。
For example, if the island does not have it, there is no way to eat it, and you will not be able to step on the fruit. If you eat protein and fish protein all day long, you will not live long, and you will not live long. It must be starchy, so it must be exchanged.
例えば、あの島では、それがなければ食べることもできないし、その実を踏むこともできず、一日中プロテインと魚のプロテインを食べていて、長生きできません。でんぷん質なので交換する必要があります。
So that island, the Matsu Islands, can be seen from the other side, and almost every island can see the other side.
そのため、その島、馬祖列島は反対側から見ることができ、ほとんどすべての島で反対側を見ることができます。
This is because he has to cling to his counterpart
それは彼が相手にしがみつかなければならないからです
So he's obviously going to catch Yu and come here and live for a while
だから彼は明らかにユウを捕まえてここに来てしばらく暮らすつもりだ
or seasonal
または季節限定
not a permanent resident
永住者ではない
Definitely Not
絶対にありません
can you answer this question
この質問に答えていただけますか
for this I
このために私は
this is the last side
これが最後の面です
Thanks
ありがとう
Speaking
話し中
Hello Professor Chen
こんにちは、チェン教授
I think I have a question and I want to ask you
質問があると思いますので、お聞きしたいのですが
Apart from actually seeing shellfish
実際に貝類を見る以外にも
Know that there are cultural sites other than
他にも文化的な場所があることを知ってください
Because other clues can be speculated that
他の手がかりが推測できるため、
There will be cultural relics here
ここには文化遺産があるでしょう
in this way
この上
Usually we archaeologists
普段、私たち考古学者は、
Let's go
さあ行こう
we are going to the fields
私たちは畑に行きます
when going to investigate
調査に行くとき
obviously
明らかに
not easy to see first not easy to see
見るのは簡単ではない まず見るのは簡単ではない
The first and most important thing to judge is the ecological environment
最初に判断すべき最も重要なことは生態環境です
Water is the most important
水が一番大切
if there is no water
水がない場合
people
人々
he can't live there
彼はそこには住めない
So the water source is the most important
つまり水源が最も重要なのです
So let's say we measure down this place
ここを測ってみましょう
look at him
彼を見て
How could he have no river
どうして彼には川がなかったのか
and no
そしていいえ
But what's interesting is
しかし、興味深いのは、
Measure the lower layer
下層を測定する
There are many caves entering the bay
湾に入る洞窟はたくさんあります
there is spring water on it
その上に湧き水があります
early days
初期
200 troops are stationed there
そこには200人の軍隊が駐留している
no supplies
物資がない
no water supply
給水なし
how do they live
彼らはどうやって暮らしているのか
They are washbasins
それらは洗面台です
Use the spring water at the bottom of the cliff to line the water
崖下の湧水を利用して水を張ります
includes a basin of water
水の入った盆地が含まれています
including face wash
洗顔料も含めて
do many things
たくさんのことをする
to the last
最後まで
When we go to investigate, the most important thing is to first check whether the environment is inhabited and where is the water source? Probably like this
調査に行くときに最も重要なことは、まずその環境に人が住んでいるかどうか、そして水源はどこにあるのかを確認することです。
Islands like this, of course, are places close to the sea, which is relatively safe, like being on a cliff, I can’t figure out why I’m going back there, this is also art, so let’s talk about it
こういう島はもちろん海に近くて比較的安全な場所で、崖の上みたいに何でそこに戻るのか分からない、これもアートだから話そう
If it wasn't so high, if it wasn't for its formation, which is sandy red soil, this human bone would not have been preserved for so long
もしそれがそれほど高くなかったら、その形成が砂質の赤土でなかったら、この人骨はこれほど長く保存されなかったでしょう。
Because usually our archeology will find human bones, which are usually inside the shellfish, and the shellfish is a protective layer, because the shells on it are so well covered
なぜなら、通常、私たちの考古学では人骨が発見されますが、それは通常貝の中にあり、その上の貝殻は非常によく覆われているため、貝は保護層となっています。
He said coldly that Le Zhan had nothing to do with it.
彼は、Le Zhanはそれとは何の関係もないと冷たく言いました。
he doesn't get through
他不容易透過
The laterite water of the sand has flowed away
砂のラテライト水が流れ去った
so he is dry
だから彼は乾いている
In that life his place is dry
その人生において彼の居場所は乾いている
So I guess these are the conditions
なので、これらが条件だと思います
Of course I have a good chance
もちろんチャンスは十分にあるよ
After a lifetime of archaeology, I dug up these two sentences
生涯にわたる考古学の研究を経て、私はこの 2 つの文章を掘り出しました。
Everything else is digging a lot of light
他のすべては多くの光を掘り起こしています
No one makes up
誰も仲直りしない
thanks sorry i'm out of ideas
ありがとう、ごめんなさい、アイデアがありません
Feel sorry
気の毒だと思う
Thanks
ありがとう
Is there any more?
他にもありますか？
I am a southern nation
私は南の国です
Are you called a Pulician?
あなたはピュリシアンと呼ばれていますか？
Because when I arrived in Ryukyu
というのは、私が琉球に来たとき、
he kept that time
彼はその時間を守った
But it's like this from the mainland
でも本土から来るとこんな感じ
He said no, we are a southern democracy, so we don’t care about it.
彼は、「いいえ、私たちは南部の民主主義国家だから、そんなことは気にしない」と言いました。
just to leave a little place
ほんの少しの場所を残すために
that language has six or five
その言語には6つか5つある
no
いいえ
Another one is Beijing Yuanren and this
もう一つは北京元連とこれです。
But naturally they say the term "big Buddha"
しかし当然彼らは「大仏」という言葉を言います。
and this
この
These
これらは
this
これ
because we are old
私たちは年をとったから
still not sure
まだわからない
Thanks
ありがとう
The Lycians are in the middle of the Pacific Ocean
リュキア人は太平洋の真ん中にいます
that is now next
それは今次です
Since the South Island universe is a kind of country since Beijing
南島の宇宙は北京以来の一種の国なので
In the South Island Universe we are talking about, there used to be a man named Marel Polaris
私たちが話している南の島の宇宙には、かつてマレル・ポラリスという男がいました。
he is not australian
彼はオーストラリア人ではありません
The Austronesian universe we are talking about
私たちが話しているオーストロネシアの宇宙
napoles is to the east
ナポレは東にあります
a district in the middle of the pacific east of vip doppin
vip doppinの太平洋東部の真ん中にある地区
About Peking Man because he is 500,000 to 600,000 years old
北京原人の年齢は50万～60万歳なので
From now on, if he is not now, he cannot be compared with our current race.
今後、彼が今でなければ、私たちの現在の種族と比較することはできません。
because he is a branch of anthropology
なぜなら彼は人類学の分野だからです
He is called Homo erectus pecinesis
彼はホモ・エレクトス・ペシネシスと呼ばれています
Homo erectus Beijing species
ホモ・エレクトス北京種
He is hundreds of thousands of years old
彼は何十万年も生きています
Many of us think that the Chinese are Beijing
私たちの多くは中国人は北京人だと思っています
The main line is Pekingese
主流は北京人
wrong
間違い
out of africa theory
アフリカからの脱出理論
There are two different things with Beijingers
北京人とは2つの異なる点がある
Because in those early days, those people felt that
なぜなら、当時の人々は次のように感じていたからです。
We are now probably after we came out of Africa
私たちは今、おそらくアフリカを出た後にいるでしょう。
It probably came out around 60,000 years ago
およそ6万年前に誕生したと考えられています
Only came out between 50,000 and 60,000 years
5万年から6万年の間にのみ出現した
Distributed all over the world
世界中に分布
This is probably like this
これはおそらくこんな感じです
Thanks
ありがとう
Just now you asked me that the whole teacher was slightly ahead of schedule
たった今、先生全員が予定より少し早まったと聞きましたね
I'm a researcher
私は研究者です
To suddenly say that the US job is written similar to the investment
アメリカの仕事は投資と同じように書かれていると突然言うのは
The question I just asked is
私が今尋ねた質問は、
The archaeologist you found has been back and forth
あなたが見つけた考古学者は行ったり来たりしています
Then you were sometimes protected on your back just now
そしたらさっきも時々背中で守られてたよね
I'm thinking maybe it's also because of the carbon build-up
もしかしたらカーボンの蓄積も原因かと思います
But for soils that have a handover effect
ただし、ハンドオーバー効果のある土壌の場合
It is not easy to distinguish between various protections
さまざまな保護を区別するのは簡単ではありません
I feel at ease when I was a flower girl like this when I was a child
子供の頃こうやって花売りをしてると安心する
The second point is that you are here
2番目のポイントは、あなたがここにいるということです
Dig up to 8000 years ago
8000年前まで掘る
7000 years of volume guide
7000年分のボリュームガイド
Is it possible to continue digging at this amount?
この量で掘り続けることは可能でしょうか？
1,000 years, 4,000 years, and 3,000 years can be found
1000年、4000年、3000年が見つかる
and that's it
以上です
thank you thank you
ありがとうありがとう
Number one, you're low on power
第一、電力が不足しています
coaching, coaching very happy
コーチング、コーチングとても幸せです
Because in fact, it is probably carbonic acid
だって実際は炭酸なんだろうから
is that it was planted in this layer
この層に植えられたということです
It itself has protection against the energy body
それ自体がエネルギー体に対する保護を持っています
For example, in our archeology in Taiwan
たとえば、台湾の考古学では
The original businessman is planted to produce human bones
元の実業家は人骨を生産するために植えられる
Because how it was planted inside
内部にどのように植えられたかというと、
So it can only come out after being planted
植えてからしか出てこないので
The protection I just mentioned is useful
先ほど述べた保護は役に立ちます
the second you talk about this
このことについて話した瞬間に
i'm so sorry
ごめんなさい
Can you still dig in eight days?
8日以内にまだ掘ることができますか？
I have to answer this
これに答えなければなりません
Because of that whole chair you just watched Zai Cangchang's
その椅子全体のせいで、あなたはザイ・チャンチャンの作品を見ただけです
Of course you can dig
もちろん掘ることもできます
But those of us who do archaeology often have a principle
しかし、考古学をやっている私たちにはしばしば原則があります。
The smaller the area to dig
掘る面積が狭いほど
The more information obtained, the more
得られる情報が多ければ多いほど、
we're going to stop
私たちはやめます
because if you dig again
もう一度掘ったら
It's probably amazing. I need to add a little more to your business.
おそらく素晴らしいと思います。あなたのビジネスにもう少し追加する必要があります。
But we have to think about the descendants of our archaeologists
しかし、私たちは考古学者の子孫について考えなければなりません
Because all subjects are closer to Nikkei
すべての科目が日経に近いため
His current technology may be better than ours in the future
彼の現在の技術は将来的には私たちの技術よりも優れているかもしれません
we gotta save some sanity for them
彼らのために正気を保っておかなければなりません
this is the point
これがポイントです
Thanks
ありがとう
Mr. Liu
劉さん
teacher sorry
先生ごめんなさい
bother your time
時間をかけてください
I have a question
質問があります
I study
私は勉強します
previous climate
以前の気候
besides
そのほか
China's climate change in the past 2000 years
過去2000年間の中国の気候変動
I think
私が思うに
Southeast coast
東南沿海
Talk to Teacher Chen
チェン先生と話す
Measure the elderly
高齢者を測定する
About 7 or 8 years old
7、8歳くらいかな
7, 8, 7 years now
現在7、8、7年間
they were
彼らはいた
our ancestors
私たちの先祖
very early in the southeast
南東のかなり早い段階で
Southeast China and South China
中国南東部と中国南部
there were activities at that time
当時活動がありました
Measure the elderly
高齢者を測定する
At the time
当時の
performance of life and climate
生命と気候のパフォーマンス
Is it with South China
中国南部と一緒ですか
The generation on the southeast coast
南東海岸の世代
Thanks
ありがとう
actually related
実際に関連している
I believe it should not be a small area problem
狭い地域の問題ではないと思います
For example, let me make a metaphor
たとえば、比喩をしてみましょう
Like we just talked about sea level
先ほど海面の話をしたように
Sea level rise is after the ice age
海面上昇は氷河期以降
During the ice age, its sea level was about 120 meters away from the present
氷河期には海面は現在より約120メートル離れていた
lower so low
とても低い
So it's hard for us to find it now
だから今はそれを見つけるのが難しい
Because it must be close to the sea and must be under the sea.
海に近いし、海の中にあるはずだから。
Then the rise is from slowly rising slowly to
その後、上昇はゆっくりとゆっくりと上昇し、
It was only about 6,000 years ago that it was relatively stable
比較的安定していたのはわずか約 6,000 年前までです
During the 8,000 years, of course, there was a little gap between about 1 or 2 meters.
もちろん、8,000年間の間には、1〜2メートル程度の小さな隙間がありました。
So presumably this climate change is global
したがって、おそらくこの気候変動は地球規模のものであると考えられます
Of course, locality doesn't matter that much.
もちろん、地域性はあまり関係ありません。
I'm going to say this
これを言うつもりです
Thanks
ありがとう
I really want to ask about the Japanese scriptures
日本の経典についてどうしても聞きたいのですが
Their savanna pottery also developed 10,000 years ago
彼らのサバンナ陶器も1万年前に発展しました
It is also believed that they are talking to fish
魚と会話しているとも考えられています
It's like saying it belongs to Zhuang
それは荘のものだと言っているようなものだ
Sorry, I'm not sure how to define it
ごめんなさい、どう定義すればいいのか分かりません
I think this thing is very similar to the marine industry with a small number of people.
これは少人数の水産業とよく似ていると思います。
maybe there is something related
もしかしたら何か関係があるかもしれない
Don't want professors to behave in this respect
教授にはこの点での振る舞いをしてほしくない
thank him for this
これについて彼に感謝します
The test of Japanese programs is divine writing
日本語プログラムのテストは神聖な文章です
Divine language and other culture
神の言語とその他の文化
They can find around 12,000 years
彼らは約12,000年前を見つけることができます
It also appeared in the later period of the army
陸軍後期にも登場
Their scriptures are thicker and thicker
彼らの経典はますます分厚くなっています
very crude scriptures
非常に粗雑な経典
probably like this
おそらくこんな感じ
Basically because Japan basically it's islands
基本的に日本は基本的に島だから
island country
島国
So it's still a form or an island life form
まだ形というか島の生命体なんですね
Of course Japan has many
もちろん日本にもたくさんあるよ
So now there is a country in the world that studies islands called the Small Island Association
それで今、世界には小島協会と呼ばれる島を研究する国があります。
is the island
島です
It only studies populations that cannot exceed 100,000
100,000 を超えない集団のみを調査します
This area cannot exceed
この領域を超えることはできません
I can't remember, and it's very clear that tens of square kilometers are like this
思い出せないけど、数十平方キロメートルがこんな感じだということははっきりしている
Zhou Research Isle
周研究小島
Because the distance between the big island and the small island is actually quite big.
大きな島と小さな島の間の距離は実際にはかなり大きいからです。
It's quite a big gap
かなり大きなギャップですね
But basically relying on the sea is related to the sea
でも、基本的に海に依存するということは海に関わることです。
Oshima still has some
大島にはまだある
For example, we have so many in Taiwan
たとえば、台湾にはたくさんあります
Later, the aborigines all ran away and all lived on the mountain.
その後、原住民たちは皆逃げ出し、山に住み着きました。
But was it chased?
でも追われたのかな？
no
いいえ
It turned out to be suitable for mountains and hills
山や丘に適していることがわかりました
they go to the mountains and hills
彼らは山や丘に行きます
it won't be on the plains
平地にはないだろう
This is another one
これはもう一つです
We spent too long and I will not talk more
あまりにも長い時間を過ごしたので、これ以上は話さない
Thanks
ありがとう
This our vice president is taking the exam
こちらの副社長が試験を受けています
this test me
これは私をテストします
This text teacher said
このテキストの先生はこう言いました
All chairs are important to us
すべての椅子は私たちにとって重要です
Of course there are chairs
もちろん椅子もございます
by its nature
その性質上
its size its scale its integrity
その規模、その規模、その完全性
This hierarchy is a false name
この階層は偽名です
But the importance is actually important
でもその重要性は実際には重要だ
But some so-called unimportant
しかし、いわゆる重要ではないものもあります
it if many of the same chairs
同じ椅子がたくさんある場合
you don't write it's importance
あなたはそれが重要であることを書きません
it's important to separate
分けることが重要です
its layers are going to separate
その層は分離するだろう
But like Liangdao this is
しかし、これも梁島と同じように、
Taichu
太中間
because he is too little
彼は小さすぎるから
Thanks
ありがとう
Time is up
時間切れです
we are very happy today
私たちは今日とても幸せです
Professor Chen gave a wonderful speech
陳教授は素晴らしいスピーチをしました
Professor Chen is 80 years old
チェン教授は80歳
looks young
若く見える
He is a self-taught
彼は独学です
Family Scholars
家族奨学生
special come
特別に来てください
We applaud him again
私たちは再び彼に拍手を送ります
Thanks
ありがとう